<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document type="Open Screenplay Format document" version="30">
  <info uuid="8a5ec666-e362-4637-983c-036b682ce82a" draft_uuid="9fba5eb2-dfb9-4ae7-af00-b82dfb18594c" pagecount="97"/>
  <settings page_width="2100" page_height="2969" margin_top="317" margin_bottom="220" margin_left="317" margin_right="317" normal_linesperinch="6.0" element_spacing="1.00" break_on_sentences="true" dialogue_continues="true" dialogue_pagebreaks="true" cont_text="(cont'd)" more_text="(MORE)" scenes_continue="false" continued_text="CONTINUED" number_continued="true" scene_time_separator=" - " page_header="#." page_footer="" header_alignment="3" footer_alignment="3" header_first_page="false" footer_first_page="false" pages_locked="false" pagenumber_start="1" pagenumber_mode="1AB" scene_numbering="false" scenenumber_mode="1AB" scenenumber_skip_io="false" scenenumber_start="1" scenenumber_format="#" scenenumber_position="3" scenes_locked="false" auto_omit_scenes="false" omitted_text="OMITTED" dialogue_numbering="false" dialoguenumber_start="1" dialoguenumber_format="(#)" dialogue_locked="false" revision="0" show_revisions="true" show_all_revisions="true"/>
  <fadein_settings saved_with="3.0.640" last_position="1380,26" index_cards_show="2" index_cards_text_size="1" index_cards_use_folders="true" index_cards_use_colors="true" navigator_show="1" navigator_pagecount="1"/>
  <styles>
    <style name="Normal Text" builtin="1" builtin_index="0" font="Courier Screenplay" size="12"/>
    <style name="Scene Heading" builtin="1" builtin_index="1" basestylename="Normal Text" style_enter="Action" style_tab_after="Action" font="Courier Screenplay" size="12" spacebefore="2.0" keepwithnext="1" allcaps="1"/>
    <style name="Action" builtin="1" builtin_index="2" basestylename="Normal Text" style_tab_before="Character" font="Courier Screenplay" size="12" spacebefore="1.0"/>
    <style name="Character" builtin="1" builtin_index="3" basestylename="Normal Text" style_enter="Dialogue" style_tab_before="Action" style_tab_after="Parenthetical" font="Courier Screenplay" size="12" spacebefore="1.0" keepwithnext="1" leftindent="635" allcaps="1"/>
    <style name="Parenthetical" builtin="1" builtin_index="4" basestylename="Normal Text" style_enter="Dialogue" style_tab_before="Dialogue" style_tab_after="Dialogue" font="Courier Screenplay" size="12" keepwithnext="1" leftindent="508" rightindent="508"/>
    <style name="Dialogue" builtin="1" builtin_index="5" basestylename="Normal Text" style_enter="Action" style_tab_before="Parenthetical" style_tab_after="Parenthetical" font="Courier Screenplay" size="12" leftindent="330" rightindent="254"/>
    <style name="Transition" builtin="1" builtin_index="6" basestylename="Normal Text" style_enter="Scene Heading" style_tab_after="Action" font="Courier Screenplay" size="12" spacebefore="1.0" align="right" leftindent="1016" rightindent="127" allcaps="1"/>
    <style name="Shot" builtin="1" builtin_index="7" basestylename="Normal Text" style_enter="Action" style_tab_after="Action" font="Courier Screenplay" size="12" spacebefore="1.0" keepwithnext="1" allcaps="1"/>
    <header_style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
    <footer_style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
  </styles>
  <paragraphs>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>SYNOPSIS</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>This is based on the remarkable true life story of Annie Besant (847-1934) A strong orator, energetic activist and idealist, this Englishwoman mixed with the leading politicians and writers of her day. A modern women, a pioneer of the feminist movement yet a deeply spiritual person.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The script covers her journey from a deeply religious and sheltered life to gaining awareness of the poverty and misery of the the poor. By chance, she stumbles into the then popular of spiritualism, secularism and socialism and becomes a well-known activist in the trade union movement and for women's rights. In London, she was a friend of Oscar Wilde  and other society people as well as the lover of George Bernard Shaw. But she never quite threw off her spiritual side and, at the height of her popularity, suddenly turned her back on political life and joined Madame Blavatsky, the notorious Russian who founded the Theosophical Society. Annie Besant eventually became President the Society and moved to India. She adopted Krishnamurti, who went on to become a world-renown teacher and philosopher. Annie returned eventually to politics and became the only white women to head the Indian National Congress where she fought alongside Gandhi for home rule.        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>This is the story of a woman who succeeded against the odds by her power with words and became a beacon for women who followed. Yet she was also a flawed character, lacking humour and misled by men. Right up to her old age she was still searching for a truth that always seem to eluded her but finds some reconciliation in her last  years.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Our amazing tale takes us from England to America, India, Sri Lanka and Singapore as Annie pursues her passions. The story offers many opportunities in capturing life and scenes from the Victorian era, in London and the more exotic places. Apart from the roles offered to the three or four actors portraying Annie, there are many cameo performances which will excite actors.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>I would hope that funding from England, India and Singapore as well as the USA would assist the financing of production. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>THE MANY LIVES OF ANNIE BESANT</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT prison yard</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>It is 1867 in Birmingham, England. A group of prisoners are being loaded onto a windowless wagon drawn by horses. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Prison Guard</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>OK, you can bring out the two special prisoners now.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The two leaders of the Irish Republican Brotherhood and led out. They stand proud and defiant and are also led into the wagon. A policeman gets inside with the prisoners. Two policemen sit in front behind the horses. The gates open and the wagon leaves the prison yard.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>EXT: STREET SCENE</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>As the carriage rattles down the road, it enters a tunnel. A man halts the horse drawn wagon with a pistol. As it stops a mob of thirty or more men climb over a wall and surround the wagon, shooting in the air and shooting a horse. The policemen on the front are pulled off and beaten. A frightened horse is shot. The attackers try to open the door but it is locked. One tries to shoot out the lock. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Prison Wagon</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Unfortunately the policeman inside decides at that time to look through the key hole and is shot through the eye and is killed. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Police SergeanT:                 </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Ahh,Ahh</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Prisoner 1 (from inside)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Yer gone and shot the frikking policeman, yer silly bastards. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>               </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>PrIsoner 2</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Bloody mad Irishmen! Hey,look. I can get the keys off this poor bastard. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The prisoner removes the keys from the dead policeman and undoes the long chain holding them together and then  passes the keys out through a ventilation grill to one of the mob . </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext:street</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The gang unlock the door and the  prisoners inside start to jump out.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>RESCUER(Irish accent):</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Which one of you are Thomas Kelly and Timothy Deasy?  Come on , take these horses and ride like the wind. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The two men come out from the back of the wagon and are helped onto waiting horses. The gang disperse leaving the empty wagon, a dying horse, and two badly beaten policemen and a dead one. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT: Same location an hour later </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The police are cleaning up. The dead policeman's body is being removed. The police commissioner is there with a Sergeant and other men. A police constable runs up.             </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>police constable:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Sir, we have recaptured four of the prisoners hiding in the park. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>They tell us it was a gang of Irishman who wanted to rescue </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>the two leaders of what they call the Irish Republican Brotherhood.I'm afraid those two got clean away on horseback.  The other prisoners say they were not part of this and didn't know about the attack.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Police commissioner</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Well done, lad. Go and try to round up the rest.(he turns to his Sergeant). I guessed it was those micks. Well, they will be sorry if they think they can kill one of our men and escape. I want you to round up everyone with a connection to this Irish Home Rule nonsense. Nay, every bloody man with an Irish accent in this city is a suspect. We can find witnesses to identify them, don't worry.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>BELOW IS SUGGESTED SCENE FOR OPENING TITLES OF MOVIE. The scene and music in contrast to the violent action shown previously.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT: Large English Protestant Church. The camera moves slowly towards the church</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: Inside the Church</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The camera moves slowly towards the front. Inside the immense church we become aware of a diminutive figure. A girl of 7 or 8 years old is on her knees praying. She is alone. We see she is looking up with adoration at the figure of Jesus Christ.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh Lord, please hear my prayers.  I know my poppa is by your side now in Heaven. Please let him know I miss him ever so much. Also please keep Mama safe and stop my brother Henry sinning all the time. Help us, dear Jesus, to grow better each day and deliver us from evil. I am sorry you had to suffer to free us from from mortal sin. Dear Jesus, I hope you  you love me as much as I love you. When I am bigger, I promise to do your work here on Earth. I will fight the Christian fight and slay all your enemies. May God forgive those who have sinned against you (her voice is echoed by a male voice)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT:courtroom</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The image of Christ's face on the statue fades into that of a young man, looking stunned </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The camera  pulls back to show three men in the dock of a courtroom. We see a judge passing sentence on three young men in the dock. One is just 19.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>JUDGE: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>May God forgive your sins. I hereby sentence you, William Allen, Michael Larkin and Michael O'Brien to hang by the neck until dead. While you wait, for this sentence to be carried out, think of the widow and child of that poor policeman you brutally killed. Take them away.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see Annie, now a young girl of sixteen, crying in the public gallery. She is comforted by a distinguished looking man. As the men are led out they shout   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Manchester Martyrs: (shouting)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Free Ireland! Home rule for the Irish!</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The spectators begin to leave. Annie moves towards the exit with the lawyer William Roberts and his family.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Roberts:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I didn't expect such a harsh sentence. None of those lads actually fired the shot that killed the police constable. I fear they are being made an example of....they are political prisoners not criminals. I can see you are upset, Annie. Go home now with my wife and daughters. I must go down to the cells and give what comfort I can to the young men. I did my best to help with their defense but I feel I have failed them. Go now.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. The court steps</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>There is an angry crowd carrying banners. "Free the Irish patriots", "Home Rule for Ireland".  As the Roberts's family near their carriage they are pushed and threatened by the crowd. The wife and daughters are visibly scared.  But young Annie bravely steps forward and puts her hand on the chest of the aggressive man.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:(loudly and firmly)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Stop. Don't you know recognise the family of Lawyer Roberts who defended the poor men in there. Let us pass!  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Man and Crowd:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh forgive us, miss. Stand back, this is Lawyer Roberts family. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The name is echoed in the crowd and the mood changes. The protesters fall back allowing the family to leave.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. ANNIE'S BEDROOM IN INDIA</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>An old lady lies on a bed in India with a servant fanning her. We hear typical Indian sounds outside the open window.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>VO:NaRRAtor (ANNIE)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>It was the summer of 1863 when I spent in Manchester with friends of my mother, Mr and Mrs. Charles Roberts that opened my eyes to the injustice in the world. Those young men were hung in public, defiant to the end, believing in the rightness of their cause. Lawyer Roberts, as he was affectionately known among the working classes, gave his time freely to help and advise the accused who became known as the Manchester Martyrs,   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. INT William Roberts' OFFICES.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is swept up in the bustle of the busy legal office. We become aware that old Mr Roberts is quite taken with young Annie. She follows him down the stairs from his offices.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ROBERTS:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Com on, Annie, follow me. We are going visiting. You've been a great help in the office these few weeks but it is time for you to see the real world.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>iNT. Miners house. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We become aware of the contrast between THE two classes as we see the damp dingy interior of the miners  house.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>MINER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I told them the brackets were faulty, Sir, but the foreman ignored me. Bloody bucket crashed down on me leg. Can't bloody work. No compensations, "No work, no pay", 'e says. I got a wife and three kiddies to feed. I just don't know what I can do...</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>He breaks down and cries. His wife and children look hopelessly on.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ROBERTS</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Don't worry. I will take up your case with the colliery management... </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>mINER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I'm grateful that you came but Oi can't afford your fees,Sir </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ROBERTS</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Shhh, don't fret. There are no fees. I am here to help. Now tell me all the details and I will see what I can do....now you were on the early shift....</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>EXTERIOR: Annie and Roberts leave the house. They pass scenes of deprivation in the adjacent houses. Half-starved children stare out with blank eyes.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Roberts:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The miners are treated like animals, Annie. If you go to the colliery, there are girls younger than you working underground, hauling carts of coal like a donkey, half-naked because of the heat. Many of the men get injured or are overcome by the gases. It is a short harsh life for most, you know, they die of coal dust on the lungs. Coughing and coughing.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>They pass by gaunt mother holding a baby  surrounded by 9 or ten children </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mr Roberts, why do they have so many children if they have so little money? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Roberts:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Aye, they have one child almost every year after they are married. They do not know how to prevent it. A lack of education or the money to purchase preventative measures. The women are worn out by the time they get to forty.And the men are worn out by too much hard work. It's a harsh short life for these people, Annie. I do what I can to help, but I fear it is too little.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Roberts walk along streets which highlight the poverty and life in those times for the working classes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext: Public scaffold</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see the three young men climbing the steps to the scaffold with the three nooses already waiting. (In the real life only one died immediately, the rest slowly strangled, one with the executioner hanging on his feet,to hasten the end, the other with a priest holding his hand. These images might be too grewsome). </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>narraTOR:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I realised what a sheltered and privileged life I had led. The dull eyes of those half-starved children living in such poor conditions haunted me on my return to my mother in London. It was my stay in Manchester that opened my eyes and I was consumed with a desire to help others. How different was the life of the poor working people from my own experiences. My Irish ancestors, the  Woods...that was my family name... helped the royal cause hundreds of years earlier and laid the foundations of our fortunes.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Of course, my mother being Irish and my father half-Irish you can see why the fate of those young Irishmen moved me so much. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. AnniE's HOME year earlier. Early evening.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see the contrast in conditions. This is a comfortable middle-class house. There are many religious symbols around. Her mother will have an educated Irish accent and her breeding should show. In this scene. Annie, is still a child of eight years old, She and and her elder brother, Harry are about to eat a meal. There is an empty place at the head of the table. The mother makes sure they pray before eating the meal.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Mother: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, Harry, stop playing. We must say grace before the meal. Dear Lord,  bless this table and the food thou has provided to us this day. We give thanks to your bounteous gifts. Take care of our dear Papa, now sitting with you in Heaven. Help us to grow more worthy of you each day and keep our hearts and minds pure. Amen. You may now begin. Henry! Don't be greedy. Your uncle may be the Lord Mayor of London but that does not entitle you to all the potatoes in  England!          </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>MOTHER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Now I have something important to tell you. Thanks to your Uncle Reginald who has agreed to pay the school fees, you Harry will be starting at Harrow school. It is where most young gentlemen start their education. I will be moving near to the school and will take in other boys as borders to bring in some extra money. I am afraid your dear father, bless his soul, did not provide for us well after his death. You, Annie, being a girl cannot go to Harrow or any private college as your uncle does not think girls need an education. However, through a friend I have found a place in Dorset where you can be educated. It is run by a Miss Marryat, a good Christian woman. who has agreed to take you without any fees.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie: close to tears</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>No, Mummy, I don't want to leave you. Really. Please. Can't I stay with you and Harry?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>MOTHER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I am sorry, Annie. I have no choice. If you are to have an education, then this is the only way. Miss Marryat has only agreed because you will be company for her niece Amy who is about your age. You should be grateful. You will both be taught in her house in Dorset, right near the beach. It will be fun and you will have a friend to play with. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Narrator:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I was close to my mother and shed many tears when I said goodbye at the train station. The excitement on traveling on one of the early passenger trains was lost on me that day. My mother put me in the care of the guard and I was packed off with heavy heart. What I didn't know was I could not have gone to a better school in those days. Miss Marryat was a evangelical Christian but she was also a very progressive educator. It was the ideal place for the little curious and bright young girl...        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INTERIOR GUARD'S VAN.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is still eight years old. She is seated beside her suitcase and parcels and cages of chickens.        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Guard:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Ok, Miss. I told your mother I would see you here safely. We are pulling in now to Axminster Station. Starting a new school eh? Lucky you. How did you like your ride in a train? You are a real pioneer, young lady. This railway line has only just opened up. A lot of folks are scared of traveling so fast. They think their souls will be left behind as the engine picks up speed (chuckles)....there.. can you feel us slowing down as the driver puts  on the brakes. We are coming to the station. Woo, steady now. Wait and sit until we have stopped. The train wont go again until I wave this green flag.....let me lift you down to the platform. There we are. Ah, you see that man there. That's your name on his sign, ain't it. Bye, missy. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>                   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. English RAILWAY station.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie emerges with her coachman who takes her luggage and lifts her onto the cart.We hear the guard's whistle and the sound of the steam engine starting off above the clip clop of the pony's hoofs.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext. English road, with couNtryside and the sea sometimes visible.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie sits on the cart clutching her a small suitcase, looking young and vulnerable.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext. Miss MarryAt's home school, Charnmouth, DORSET.           (the house still exists)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The horse-drawn cart arrives at a large sunny house where she welcomed by Miss Marryat, a lady in her early to mid-forties with a kind face.  We see she is lame. A girl, a year or two older stands behind her.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Miss Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Welcome Annie. This is my niece, Amy. She will keep you company. You will both learn together. Come along then, let me show you to your room. After prayers to thank the Lord for your safe arrival, we can have some supper together.       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Thank you, Miss Marryat </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Miss Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We are happy to have you. And please, dear, call me Auntie</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Annie's new bedroom.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>In the bedroom, Annie unpacks her suit case. From it she takes a poster and carefully pins up a picture of Joan of Arc on the wall. And sets her Bible by the bed and a photo of her mother. We see she is a very disciplined child by the way she packs away her clothes.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. informal school room. It is a large, light room with a baby grand piano. A blackboard with an easel stands one side. There are many books on shelves.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>miss Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>At Fernhill, my pupils must learn to think for themselves. I do not want you to just memorise, or repeat after me like a silly duck. Quack,quack,quack. Hands up those who think girls are as smart or smarter than boys?  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Amy shoot up their hands giggling.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>miss Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You will learn to write properly, to appreciate the beauty of language and be transported by fine literature. You will conquer mathematics and science, lift your your soul with music while strengthening your body with physical exercise. Above all, (she becomes a little fanatical) you will learn to worship with humility, recognising only through Jesus Christ can you enter heaven. He is the one who  gave his life to atone for your sins. On Sundays you will read no other book but the Bible......(smiles) but today being Tuesday, we start by reading from 'Fabulous Histories' or the 'History of the Robins' by Mrs Trimmer. From this you will learn to respect all God's creatures and treat them well. Annie, would you like to begin reading....      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT./EXT. Various scenes and SOUNDS AROUND SCHOOL</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see the two girls, sometimes with other children, reading, getting music lessons ( special teacher), learning Latin and German, playing sports like archery or going on long rambles in the countryside and enjoying picnics on the beach. We also see many scenes of Annie in praying in church. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: annIE;S Bedroom at Fernhill.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is stripped to the waist and see her scouring her self, flagellation, with a homemade whip of twigs.  You can see she is not too serious but she still winces with the pain.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I pledge my life to the Lord Jesus.I pledge my life to the Lord Jesus. I pledge my life to the Lord Jesus </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: Miss Marryat's dining room </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The diners say prayers. Mildred the maid brings in the dishes. Amy and Miss Marryat tuck into their food but Annie does not eat. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>miss Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>What is wrong? Annie, why are you not eating? Are you ill? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I have decided to fast like St Catherine of Sienna. To deny myself food until His holy spirit enters me.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Miss Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Miss Marrayat wisely does not argue. and continues calmly. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Very well Annie. I can see you have made up your mind on this matter. Far it it from me to sway you from following a saint. Mildred, will you please clear Annie's plate.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The others resume eating and chatting while Annie sits isolated.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Annie's bedroom evening time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is laying on the bed. There is a knock at the door. Miss Marryat enters. She is carrying a plate with a slice of apple pie on it.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Miss Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, you missed dinner as well as lunch. St Catherine fasted because her mother was forcing her to  marry a man she did not love. Jesus knows you love him and that you would make sacrifices for him. But he wants you strong to fight his good fight. God has produced this food from the fertile earth which he created. Do you want to throw his good works in his face? Let's ask him now Annie. Get on your knees and pray.... Oh Lord guide this servant into the right action so that she pleases you. Keep her on the path to good health so that her spirit remains strong forever to worship you. Amen.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>They both get up. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>miss marryat:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Do you think you might now like to have a piece of pie, Annie.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Yes, Auntie, I think Jesus may want me to eat. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Miss Marryat leaves smiling to herself.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT School Room </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Amy and Annie with other boys and girls are learning music from a male tutor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: Garden</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Amy are learning archery</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>EXT BEACH</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The two girls picnic on the sandy beach  with Ms Marriot and the maid.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. Woods</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see the girls on a nature trip. Ms Marryat is pointing out trees and plants. We get a glimpse of a fox or badger. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT schoolroom:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see the two girls writing and studying. We see them growing up in these scenes.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We are left with the impression of an idyllic and full life in the school.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ms Marryat's Garden.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie now 14 years old is reading a newspaper.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:              </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Auntie. Have you heard of Charles Darwin? He has just published a book called The Origin of the Species. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>According to this newspaper report, Darwin says we  developed from sea creatures, changing over millions of years. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Miss Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Yes, he apparently thinks we were once apes. Annie, the Bible tells us men were placed on Earth by God created in his own image. Would you believe this crackpot adventurer or the Word of the Lord written down by the prophets? Don't fill your head with that nonsense.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie continues to read, and become thoughtful.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: schoolroom</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see Annie grow into a young adolescent of 13 or 14.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>miss Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, this is a complex book.  We need to dig deeper. What secret did Rochester have? Why did the author, Charlotte Bronte, bring in this element? What action did the revelation on Jane Eyre? Why was this essential for the narrative?  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: SChoolroom </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>There are French phrases on the chalk board. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Reading in French: Notre-Dame de paris,ou simplement Nortre-Dame pour Parisians,est la,cathedral de l'archidiocese n'est pas plusgrande cathedrales francaises , mai elle est indicutaablement, l'une des plus remarquables qu'ait produites l'architecture...  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Miss Marryat: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Tres bien, Madamoselle Woods. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INt. School room. LATER DATE  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>.....the mysterious horseman turned his black steed around and galloped off into the night. The end.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>MISS Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Well done Annie, what an exciting tale. I think you might become a famous writer like my brother, Captain Marryat. He is well-known  since he wrote "Midshipman Easy." Freddy, was quite a war hero and had many adventures at sea. I did so envy him. Looking after mother and my stupid leg kept me here. You will have no such things to stop you, my girls. Use your heads and you can conquer the world, God willing.  Oh, Captain Marryat also wrote "Children of the Forest." You may may enjoy that. Borrow the copy I have on the shelf over there.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Fernhill HoUse kitchen ( later date)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The two girls clatter into the room full of high spirits. We can see they have both grown into young women. Amy is more developed physically, while Annie remain quite slim but we can see the budding womanhood. A maid is preparing the breakfast and putting china on the table. Miss Marryat is sitting down at the table already. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Miss Marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Girls, sit down. I have some sad news for you. I am going to Europe. My nephew has to go to Germany to see an eye specialist.  He has cataracts and will go blind if he is  not operated on. The best surgeon is located in Bonn. I will be accompanying him (pause).....and you two will come with me! </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The girls squeal with excitement. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>When Auntie, when?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> MISs marryat:    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We get a steamer from Southampton next week. I have had passports made and written to your mothers for permission. You can brush up on your languages while there. You already speak German and know a little French. It's time you saw a bit more of the world. We will try to visit Paris after Germany.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The girls are excited and start speaking in a mix of German and French. Breakfast is almost forgotten in the excitement. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>miss marryat:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Come on girls, we must not keep the food waiting. First we must say grace. For what we are about to receive, may the Lord God make us truly thankful. May we begin and live this day and every day, worthy of You. Amen                           </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The girls start to eat, but we can see they are still highly excited by their glances at each other. Miss Marryat notices but smiles indulgently.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXt. German citIES and SIGHT </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see Annie and Amy enjoying being tourists in various locations. The cousin is pushed around in a wheel chair with his eyes bandaged. The young German University boys are attracted to the two English girls, especially to Amy who had grown into a rather voluptuous girl. Miss Marryat hurries the girls away from this unwanted attention. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>miss marryAt:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Come on, girls, tomorrow we are going to stay at a chateau on the Rhine. I understand the Marquis of Douglas and Lord Charles, the sons of the Duke of Hamilton, are staying there for the summer.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>EXT: CHATEAU  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see Annie and Amy at a  large chateau. They are on the lawn with two boys. One boy is flirting with Amy but Annie is keeping her distance from the other boy.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>AMY:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>William, have you even kissed a girl, come on, tell the truth.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Charles:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Course I have. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>AMY:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I don't believe you. I bet you have only kissed your sister. They look like virgin lips to me! What say you Annie? Does William have virgin lips? (Giggles)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:(Pulls a face)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I don't know William  usually has chocolate coated on them from all the bonbons he eats! </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>RODNEY:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I could show you how to kiss, Annie. The girl next door to us in Cambridge showed me last summer how to kiss properly. You start like this.       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Rodney leans forward with lips pursed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Stop now Rodney, my lips are only used in prayer to the Lord Jesus. And to kiss the cross like this ( she lifts the cross around her neck). There are more important things than your silly kissing.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie goes back to reading her book while Amy teases and flirts with William. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXTERIOR SCENES IN Paris. 1861/2</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see Annie, Amy and Ms Marryat visiting walking in Paris streets and entering the Louvre.Note the Eiffel Tower has not yet been erected.             </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>INT: Louvre</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Amy and Annie race ahead of Miss Marrayat                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Amy:                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh look Annie, you can see his little willy. See! See!  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie refuses to look at the sculpture of the nude Spartacus and hurries on. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: Louvre</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie stands rapt in front of painting "Christ appearing to the three Mary's". </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Amy:Impatiently</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, do come along, Annie....</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext. Cafe in paris. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Miss Marryat and a friend are drinking coffee. The two girls are close by. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>FRIEND:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Have you heard the Bishop of Ohio is coming to Notre Dame next week. He is a good friend of my husband. The Bishop will be conducting a Confirmation in the cathedral. Would Annie like to participate, do you think?  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I heard, oh Auntie, may I? Please. I know all the catechism off by heart already.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Miss marryAt:                     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Why doesn't that surprise me. It's all a bit to flashy for my taste, too near the Catholics,  but I have no doubts of your sincerity. If you really want to do this, Annie, it can be arranged.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. NotrE Dame CATHEDral.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We witness Annie and other girls overawed by the whole event. The richness of the vestments is in contrasts to the simplicity of the English churches. We see her face transfixed. Annie, dressed all in white, is on her knees at the altar. The Bishop marks her forehead with the cross.         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BISHOP: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Be sealed with the gift of the Holy Spirit.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXt. Battlefield</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>In her mind, we see a flash of her dressed as Joan of Arc on a horse.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I fight for your Kingdom, Sweet Jesus. I am prepared sacrifice my life for you, my Lord</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT NoTRE DAME Cathedral</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The ceremony rich in pageantry. Annie is obviously struck and impressed by this. She leaves full of the Holy Spirit.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT.  by boat to England. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and the others are on the boat crossing the English channel returning to England. We sense this is the closing of a chapter of her life.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>NARRATOR:Over images of the boat</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We returned to Fernhill for a few months. Europe had opened our eyes to a wider world and my French and German were now perfect. Miss Marryat refused to teach us anything more - insisting we learned to self-study. She was preparing us for the real world. I returned to my mother's house in Harrow but had no idea how soon I would have to face the reality of a world so different from the comfortable middle class bubble which up to now had protected me.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Wood home</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is in the parlor of her mother's home. Her mother is sewing while Annie is reading.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>mother:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, you always have your nose in a book. Come with me today. I promised Aunt Mary that you would help out at St Barnaby's. The place has been left empty and she is helping clear it up so services can resume. You could help her for a few weeks until you decide what to do next.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>iNT. Dusty church.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>There are a number of women picking up items and hanging drapes. The sunlight catches the dust as a young man sweeps the floor. Mrs Wood and Annie enter. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Mother:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Hello Mary, this is my daughter Annie. She's recently returned from Europe and finished her schooling in Dorset. She has returned home to me. She can give a hand here in the Church she has nothing to do for the next few weeks.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>mary:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Bless you child, we can do with all the help we can. 'Tis sad to see the house of God so neglected. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>mother:                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie needs to be kept busy. They say the devil makes work for idle hands. And who's the young man over there...</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Mary: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh that is a young curate down from Oxford. Part of the seminary training. His name is Frank..er Besant. Handsome lad, eh?  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>It is obvious that Frank has noticed the sweet 16 year-old. As Annie wanders around, Frank approaches her. Frank is handsome in a rather ascetic way. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>FRANK:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Hello, my name is Frank. I haven't seen you before. Do you live in the neighbourhood?  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I'm Annie. Yes, I have just returned home. I've finished schooling now. I went to Europe for a few months but now I am home again. My mother wants me to help out here... Aunt Mary said that you are a clergyman.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>FRANK:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Not yet, I am finishing my studies and then I can be ordained. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie: (very ernest)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>How wonderful to give your life to Christ. To serve our dear Lord, night and day must be so satisfying</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>FRANK: (A little taken aback)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Er, Yes....</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I believe Jesus has plans for me too....</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Mother:Interrupting</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, come and help over here now</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie breaks off the conversation. Frank obviously is not so fervent in his Christian belief but is nevertheless attracted to this serious young woman. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. TRAIN STATION. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>A party of elderly people are boarding the train for a trip to the seaside led by Aunt Mary.  Annie and Frank are helping them board and find their seats. Annie and Frank sit next to each other. Both react when their knees accidentally touch. It is obvious neither of them have much experience of the opposite sex and are painfully aware of the other.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. Different scenes at the seaside.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The Church group enjoy different activities and Frank and Annie are pushed together being younger than the others. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT train station</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is seeing Frank off. He is still rather stiff and awkward.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Frank:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I am sorry I have to leave early, Annie,but I have to get back to my studies in Oxford. I have enjoyed our week together. Em, I think it is important for a clergyman to have a wife to work with him in a parish, don't you think so?    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Yes, I suppose so.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>frank:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Good. I would like us to get married, Annie</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is taken aback and does not answer, but Frank takes this this silence as assent, awkwardly kisses her on the cheek and strides off to catch his train.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT/EXT; THE wood's home</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Frank is seen knocking at the door. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Don't tell him I'm here.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>MOTHER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You have to be honest with him Annie. He writes every week. And he is a handsome lad.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie hides upstairs and Mrs Wood answers the door.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Mother:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Why Frank, what a lovely surprise. I am afraid Annie isn't home but she will be sorry to have missed you. Come on in.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>   frank:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I am just in London for the day attending a ministry seminar. I had hoped to see Annie. I am sure she has told you about our engagement, and as there is no longer a Mr Woods, may God rest his soul, then I seek your approval.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>mother:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I would certainly be happy to see Annie married to a man of the cloth. She has certainly spoken of dedicating herself in the service of the Church. But do remember Frank, she is young, not yet seventeen. I would be happy to see you together but I do think she should wait a year or two year. Until she is a little older.  I hope you understand Frank. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>frank:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Woods, I would not want to rush into such a solemn partnership before the eyes of God unless both parties were mature and ready for commitment. We can discuss this again. I must now take my leave, to catch the coach back to Oxford. Please tell Annie I came by.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>As soon as he is gone, Annie bursts into the room.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mother, you encouraged him! I never agreed to get married.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>mother:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Well, you must have the courage to tell him yourself. It is all very embarrassing. How can you call it off now? ....  dear, dear don't distress yourself. Being a clergyman's wife means you can help people. Isn't that what you are always saying, "I want to help people?"  Anyway, I have bought you some time. The marriage is still a long way off and you may grow to love him. And frankly, I cannot go on supporting you. It has been a struggle financially and my health is not good. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Anyway, I have asked Mrs and Mrs Roberts in Manchester if you can go and stay with them. You cannot hide away here all the time. Mr Roberts is a famous lawyer and he is willing to have you help in his office. If you agree, then I will write to him and tell him you will be arriving next week.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>naRRATOR:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The time I spent in Manchester with Mr Roberts made me shockingly aware of the injustice in the world. I returned from Manchester with the images of the struggling miners and those deaths of dedicated Irish patriots remaining in my mind. My eyes had been opened to many things but, unfortunately, nobody, not even my mother, had prepared me for marriage and what that might actually mean...   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>int. A bedroom 1867</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Frank are semi-dressed in bed. Close up on Annie's face as Frank is grunting and thrusting. Her eyes are alarmed and shocked. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>int./EXT. Cuts of SOFT FOCUS ANNIE IN IDEALISED CHURCH WEDDING and ANNIE fantaSIES OF DISTRIBUTING GIFTS TO GRATEFUL PARISHIONERS.  ALL INTER-CUT with brutal intercourse IMAGES   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Frank snores while Annie sheds tears. It is obviously a shocking and traumatic revelation for Annie.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT.EXT Idyllic Vicarage.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see Annie, now older and with two children, sitting around the breakfast table. She is opening a letter.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh, my latest short story has been accepted by 'Family Herald' magazine.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>FRANK:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I wish you would not waste so much time on writing those frivolous stories. You need to attend to parish duties.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:(snappy)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You were happy enough to keep the 2 guineas I earned with the last one.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>FranK:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>As you know Annie, as the head of the household, all income must come to me. Let us not debate that again. Sibsey is my first parish. I am now the vicar of St Margaret's church. I would remind you that your behaviour at Cheltenham College caused many problems and did not reflect well on me.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Those silly wives of your colleagues could only talk about babies or baking. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>FRANK</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You didn't try to fit in. You were rude and arrogant. I had to put up with your hysteria and mysterious illnesses which kept you in bed for weeks. We have the chance of a new start here in Sibsey.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>By the way, I showed your texts on the scriptures to the Bishop and he was very impressed. I wish you would spend more time on these and helping me with my sermons than sitting up at night writing for these trashy London magazines. Lately you have not been contributing to these Church's pamphlets.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>                      ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>It's .. just ... I am finding some contradictions in the Bible, and it makes it difficult to write with the true spirit. Since we have been here I have see so much suffering, even our village, women dying of childbirth, others worn out by too many children, farm workers unable to work because of injuries, is the really God's Will? Frank, we nearly lost our own child because whooping cough and she is still weak. Mabel suffered so much. Why does God permit this? I need you to help  me understand.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Frank:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Why do you have to question everything? God's purpose is not made known to us. Only the Bishop himself can give you such answers. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Cut to exterior of a grand country house, home of the Bishop. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie enters the house led by the Bishops' housekeeper</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>HOUSEKEEPER/SECRETARY</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The Bishop got your letter and he is happy to give you a few minutes to discuss the contents. He admires the Reverend Frank Besant, one of his most promising young clerics. Lord Bishop, Mrs Besant is here. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Interior. outside the office</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see the Bishop genially greet her as she enters his office. We view them both through the glass in the door. We cannot hear the Conversation distinctly but as the discussion progresses the Bishop can be seen getting more and more angry. The door is eventually thrown open. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BISHOP</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Besant, you are a blasphemer. These ideas are dangerous. It is not your duty to ascertain the truth. It is your duty to accept and believe the Truth as laid down by the Church. I feel the devil has got into you. I will be dispatching a letter to your husband immediately. Do not question the word of the Lord. May He have mercy on your soul. Good day to you! </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. DRiveway of Bishop's HOUSE</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie hurries down the drive away from the house. It is obvious she is not cowed by the recent exchange. The troubled Bishop watches her from the window as she walks away. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Int./EXT. Annie back in Sibsey visits A parishioner. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>A woman having a difficult birth. Baby dies. It is obvious Annie lacks a bedside manner.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I am so sorry you have lost your child. But while it is hard to accept, it does relieve you of the burden of another mouth to feed. My husband will put the child in God's hands. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie sweeps out of the cottage leaving a stunned family behind.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT: Churchyard</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie attends graveside with baby casket.Frank conducts ceremony.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT/INT ST Margaret's (SIBSEY) CHURCH</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is seen walking up to the church and slipping inside. She looks around to see if she is alone. She climbs on the pulpit and begins to speak, hesitantly at first but with growing confidence. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Would Jesus ignore the cries of the poor? Can we as Christians just shut our eyes and ears to their pleas? It is our duty as servants of the Lord to offer succor to those in need. Why do you not interceded on behalf of those with no voice? Why do you not answer our prayers. Did you look down and see my daughter gasping for breath due to hooping cough, barely hanging on to life. What had that poor child ever done to deserve that torture? Were you punishing her or me? And the poor farm workers, a short walk from   this Church, God's house, when do they get your mercy? Are you unable to help because you are impotent and not omnipotent? Are you not all powerful. I raise my voice to demand answers...    ( FADE DOWN)   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. CHURCH on other days</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see Annie continue to grow as an orator, her speeches becomes less religious and more political.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>What is your hope? A heaven in the clouds? I point to a heaven obtainable on earth. You serve warmly a god  unknown and invisible. A projected shadow on your own imaginations. Yet you can only serve coldly the brother at your side. If you want the inspiration of your own feelings and sensitivities, keep to your bible and creeds. But if you want inspiration to work, then walk down the squalid streets in the East End of London or the back streets of Manchester. If you are inspired by tenderness when you look at the wounds of Jesus who died in Judah years ago, but yet find not the same for the man and women dying in England today. I want you to hear the truth. Perhaps it is time for you to get off your knees and march for compassion. Use you voices to draw attention to the suffering of others. Put you hands together not to pray but to pull the poor out of poverty. . Men and women of Sibsey, open your eyes to reality. He will not be coming to your aid no matter how sincere your call...            </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>INT CHURCH. SUNDAY</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The congregation is taking Holy Communion, one by one they walked to the front but Annie sat still in her seat. She remained there despite Frank looking pointedly at her. Finally she walks out.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext. Church </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Parishioner exiting the Church are glancing over at Annie. Frank eventually comes over to Annie. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>FRANK:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Why did you not take Holy Communion? Annie, people noticed. This is the second time you have not come up to share the blood and flesh of Christ.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I can no longer pretend Frank. I have to many questions. I would be a hypocrite if I took part in something so holy without my head and heart being fully in it. I just cannot do it any longer.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>FRANK:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Your are the wife of the Vicar. How do you think this looks to my parishioners? How can I tell them my own wife is a disbeliever? If the Bishop hears of this, and he will, I could lose my position here. Be reasonable, Annie. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I just cant, Frank, I'm sorry...</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie rushes off leaving Frank alone outside his Church.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>INT: VICARAGE</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is seated reading when her husband enters later.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>frank:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You did not even come to Church. This is another Sunday where you were absent. You are the vicar's wife but you skip Communion. You make me look a fool. It cannot go on. Either you come to Church with me next Sunday or there is no place for you here. Do you understand. This will stop, Annie. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. train carriage</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is seated next to her daughter Mabel.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>MABEL:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Where are we going? Why couldn't Digby come with us? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We are going to London and see Grandmama. Your brother has to stay behind to keep your  father company. I'm going to get a job and look after us both. Don't worry, darling, (Annie turns to the carriage window and is softly crying). </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Int. posh house in london   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is seen working as a housekeeper, doing chores. She no longer looks so smartly dressed and appears tired.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>LADY:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Besant, will you please ensure  the best dinner set is laid out for tonight's function. And, by the way, you must keep that child of yours quiet. I heard her crying last night. We have allowed you to have your daughter with you but she must not disturb us. Do you understand?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Yes, Mam. I will see she is quiet. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: Annie's room </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see Annie writing at night with with her daughter beside her. The room is pretty basic. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>mabel:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mummy, I want to go home. I miss Digby. And I cannot go into the garden here. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Hush child, we have to stay here for just a while. I will find you somewhere nice to live soon. I promise you. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>INT: Mrs Wood's house. Annie visits her mother who is sick.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>MOTHER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Pray with me Annie, I do not think I have much time. It distresses me to see you you live apart from Frank. A wife must stick to her husband. And what about little Digby? A young boy needs his mother. I pray to the good Lord to bring you back to you place at your husband's side.Come now Annie, let us pray together: Oh Lord, our heavenly father, .....  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext: Outside HALL AT NIGHT. We see NATIONAL SECULAR SOCIETY POSTER with Bradlaugh as speaker. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is walking past and sees the poster. The meeting is in progress. She slips inside.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Packed hall.ON stage is the speaker charles Bradlaugh. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is mesmerised by the speaker who is not only an impressive orator but a tall handsome man with charisma.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BRADLAUGH:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I cannot follow the Christians who try to crawl through life on their knees, while I stride through mine on my feet.... I am withou't an idea of God. The word 'God' to me is a sound conveying no clear or distinct affirmation. I do not deny God because I cannot deny that of which I have no conception, and the conception of which by its affirmers is so imperfect that he is unable to define it for me.... Liberties chief foe is theology.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>As the meeting breaks up Annie, still only 26 years old, slim and attractive, moves to the front and as the admirers disperse she starts asking him questions. Bradlaugh is both amused and impressed by this earnest young woman.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mr Bradlaugh, you claim there is no God but do you not see the hand of divinity all around you? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BrADLAUGH (teasing):</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You mean in the faces of the half-starved wretches living a few doors away from this hall?  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>No Sir, but I see his hand in the delicacy of the flower and the song of the bird.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BrADLAUGH:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>There are precious few flowers in the streets of London and the pigeons nest in the sooty chimneys above and have no song. There is little to sing about for the poor working people of London. Where is your God in a place where we really need Him?   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie (bEginning to smile):</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I must confess, Sir, I find him missing too often.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BradLAUGH:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We have to leave now, they want to close up the Hall. Why don't you walk with me to my lodgings nearby and we can discuss this further.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT: Streets of London</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Bradlaugh walk together in animated conversation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: Bradlaugh's small living room. It is full of books and rather untidy. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie has to clear books of a chair to sit down. She looks around. She picks up a copy of 'The National Reformer' magazine and scans it as Bradlaugh prepares tea and stokes the fire. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Is there no Mrs Bradlaugh? Are you not married?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I am married. She is...not well.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Not well? Then should you not be by her side? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BRadlaugh:( hesitatingly)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>She is not exactly ill. She is...an alcoholic. I love her but she is unable to stop drinking. (shakes head sadly) And you, Mrs Besant, where is your husband?   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>My husband is a clergyman( Bradlaugh laughs aloud, very amused). We separated a few months ago. It was not a happy marriage but it all came to head when I stopped attending Holy Communion. I could no longer believe the wafer and wine was the blood and flesh of Christ. And I found so many contradictions in the Bible that I begun.....FADES DOWN   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see Annie and Charles talking through the night. The fire dies down. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh:                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, Annie, you may not realise it but you are already a non-believer. I don't have to convince you. You have thought yourself into atheism without knowing it. Look, I have a proposal. Leave your house-keeping job and join me on my magazine, The National Reformer. You tell me your stories have already been published so I am sure you can assist on the editorial. How about 1 guinea a week? But you first have to join the National Secular Society      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie: Laughing </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I'm not sure I can yet deny the existence of God but, yes, I will join you and your Society. And I will gladly be part of your editorial team. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>But, I must warn you that if you take this step you will be villified by almost everyone. Called a whore and  other names. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Int: national Reformer offices</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is seen in editorial conferences with Charles Bradlaugh. They obviously get on well together. There appears a mutual attraction.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Co worker 1 </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Do you think they are lovers? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>co-worker 2</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Nah, oh they are in love alright. The attraction is there. but they both refuse to acknowledge it. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Co worker 1</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>They should get married. Look at them smiling at each other....</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>co-worker 2</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I'm afraid they are too highly principled to either become lovers or get divorces. Its sad, really. Happiness is rare these days.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>co worker 1</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Well, dear old Charles is really happy with her articles. She may be young but she works very hard. I find her a bit serious, not very chatty.... </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Co-worker 2</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I hear the boss is going to ask her to take on some of the lectures next week.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>iNT. Co-operative hall in london</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Annie is speaking on women's rights "On the political status of women" says the banner. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>When I was asked to give a lecture in this hall, I hesitated a little what to select for the subject of it. Various reasons seemed to restrict my choice to some political theme but even with this restriction the field was a wide one. But it happens to be my first lecture in a public hall, and a feeling of loyalty to my own sex made me determine that my first speech should be dedicated to the assertion of its rights; and I, therefore, chose as my subject "The political Status of Women". I am anxious that it should be clearly understood that I do not stand here as the representative of any society nor am I even a member of any; therefore any blame may be found in what I say , that blame should be leveled at myself alone., and not at the cause for which I plead. I plan to cover the following areas:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Why should the political incompetency of women receive so much attention when more pressing wrongs require a remedy?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Women are naturally unfit for to be given more voice?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>They are themselves uninterested in such matters</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The are already sufficiently represented.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Political power would draw them away from the home and me a source of domestic annoyance. Lastly we are told that women are commanded by the Bible to keep silent and be generally as unobtrusive as possible. Every great truth, it has been said, must travel though three stages of public opinion: men will say of it, first, that it is not true. Second that it is contrary to religion and lastly that everyone knew it already. The rights of man have been battled through the first two stages. Every one know men have rights. These are natural rights. Kings presidents, governments draw their authority from the will of the people. It is quite a new light to the general public that women have any rights at all. Duties, ay, they have plenty of those. Wrongs, plenty of those too, which will not be borne much longer.. Privileges? Only granted at the hands of our masters. But 'rights'?  The assertion was first met with laughter. Only now are they taking this more seriously when they see we are in earnest. , and they condescend to use little argument, and to administer a little "soothing syrup" to these fractious children.....   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INt/EXT Scenes of Annie and Charles speaking to large crowds. Including One for home rule for Ireland.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext:Riverbank</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh is in the water with his rod fishing. Annie is sitting on the bank. It is a peaceful scene.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BRADLAUGH:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Come on, Annie, I'll teach you to fish.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>No, no, I'll get wet</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BradlAUGH:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>What the fearless campaigner is scared of a little water? Come on now, give me your hand... </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie slips off her shoes and steps into the shallow river. Bradlaugh stretches out his  arm and steadies her. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Now hold the rod, bring your arm back and throw the it forward. Letting the line run free. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The action brings them both into close proximity, an awareness of their bodies. There is a moment when they might kiss but it passes.                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh:                     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Now look at the float, you see it is bobbing. You have a bite. No don't move, now pull, girl, pull!</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Excitedly: I have a fish, I have a fish. What next Charles, what next...? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Slowly wind him in. Gently but firmly reel him in. Steady or you will lose him.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:                         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>There he is, oh he so big.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh gets a net and lifts the fish into it.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh he's so beautiful. Oh Charles, I cannot let him die. Let's put him back.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Charles, releases the fish. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>bradlaugh                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh, Annie, despite your rational mind, you irrationally feel sympathy for a fish that has no brain to speak of. That was our supper you let go!   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT/EXT. Bradlaughs home"</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The two return, giggling and happy with each others company. They are met by Bradlaugh's daughters. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>bradlaugh:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Hello girls, you know Mrs Besant, Annie, why don't you go into the living room while I get some tea. No fish I;m afraid, but a big one got away... </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The girls and their father go into the kitchen. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>HYPATIA: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Daddy, why are you always with that woman. We don't like her.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ALICE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>She's so snooty. And never laughs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BraDlaugh:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I admit she doesn't find it easy to smile. But she is sincere and you know she is the best speaker in the National Secular Society by far. Give her time to warm to you. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh goes back into the drawing room with tea, followed by the girls but we sense the tension.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>braDlaugh:                 </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>There we go Annie. It was a great day. We will make a fisherman of you yet. Hypatia, why don't you play something for us.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>His daughter goes to the piano. We can see the attraction of Annie and Bradlaugh much to the disgust of his daughters. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. national reformer office</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>brADLAUGH:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Our printer is in trouble over this book. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The Fruits of Philosophy? It does not sound like a controversial book. Ohh.... I see.(flipping over the pages) </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>braDLAUGH:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You can see it contains information and advice on birth control. There are even some illustrations which make everything very clear. It was written by Dr Knowlton, a Boston medical man. Now our friend has been fined for publishing an indecent book.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>But this is just what women need to know. They are worn out by pregnancy after pregnancy and they do no have enough money to feed and cloth so many children. Charles, we must reprint this book ourselves. And not at the fancy price of this one, an affordable price that working people can buy.       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>braDLAUGH:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You realise we will also be charged in court if we do. Of course, you do! The publicity is just what the book needs. I'll tell you what, Annie, we will give some copies to the police to make sure we are prosecuted.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. women rushing to buy the book. Mixed cuts of  newspaper headlines "'IMMORAL' BOOK. Publishers FACE Prison.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>            INT. CourTroom.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Bradlaugh face the judge and prosecutor.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>  Prosecutor:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Any decent, Christian - man or woman- can see that this is an immoral book. If the Lordship, will forgive me, it not only uses words that will give offense but but the publisher has had the temerity to actually show parts of a woman's anatomy in graphic detail. We need to stop such publications getting into the hands of young people and corrupting their morals. I believe Mr Bradlaugh and Mrs Besant were well aware of the immorality of such a book yet went ahead and published it at a low price so that it could get into the hands of the less-educated classes and dangerously arousing their beastly passions.          </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Judge:(interupting)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Besant, I understand you are the wife of a clergyman. Has that man, Mr Bradlaugh, encouraged you in the foolhardy venture. I am willing, even at this late stage) to let you withdraw from this case.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>No, your honour. I cannot withdraw. It would mean withdrawing for the fight that women have to gain knowledge on how to limit their families. How to prevent unwanted pregnancies which threaten their own health and the care of her existing children. I believe this booklet should be in the hands of every married woman.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>JUDGE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Very well, the prosecution may continue.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Prosecutor:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Thank you, m'lud. The two defendants, already knowing a previous court had convicted another printer, have willfully published this indecent , piece of dirt,  knowing it will encourage immoral behaviour. It contains images of the female body that will excite men and pollute the minds of children. This godless duo are bent in bringing to an end the Christian values of the country..  (fade down)  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>...I say to you, members of the jury, as a mother of a daughter I love that it will tend to her happiness in her future as well as her health, that she will not have made to her the kind of mystery about sexual functions...</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Images flash back to her own wedding night</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>...that every man and woman must know sooner or later. Ignorance  of the duties of married life can, and does, traumatice young women. Without knowing how to limit their families, they are worn out by pregnancy after pregnancy. We have simply tried to educate married men and women to understand the reproductive system. We seek to strengthen marriage not destroy it. Population control is essential if we are to eradicate poverty in this country. We simply have too many mouths to feed and hunger will only become a daily occurrence for more of our poor citizens. ( fade down)        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>...will you convict me of</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text> indecency, will you send me to prison to share a cell with hardened criminals because Mr Bradlaugh and I seek to educate people? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Cuts of scenes in the court.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Judge:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Members of the jury, have you reached a verdict?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>foreman:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We are unanimous of the opinion that the book in question is calculated to deprave public morals but at the same time we entirely exonerate the defendants from any corrupt motive in publishing it.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>JUDGE                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Thank you, members of the jury. You are now dismissed. While the jury has sympathised with your motives, you nevertheless published a book which has been found liable to deprave the morals of the public. I have no choice but to find you guilty. Sentencing will be postponed until 28 June.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The court is closed. As Bradlaugh and Annie leave a young man approaches Annie Besant.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>SHAW:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Besant, I am Bernard Shaw, a journalist. Will you appeal the verdict? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>  ANNE:            </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Certainly we will, Mr Shaw. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>shaw:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I was very impressed with your observation on population growth. I'd like to write about this. May I call upon you some time? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:(smiling)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh Mr Shaw, are you really a journalist? You look very young. Yes, please do contact me. There is much to discuss.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. SiBSey vicarage </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Frank is reading the newspaper. We can read headlines. DIRTY DUO IN COURT. Frank is obviously agitated.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>FRANK:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>She's gone too far this time. I'm not having my daughter brought up in a home where this kind of filth is laying around. Mabel must return home.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. Annie home in london</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Frank is outside while two men from the court are dragging out the crying 7 year old girl. Annie is distraught.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> Frank:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>This is a court order Annie. You are not a fit mother. You neglect her for your political activities and speak in public about (splutters) private matters. Mabel already told me that you do not make her say her prayers at night.You have even asked her school to stop religious instruction. The courts have awarded me custody and she will return to Sibsey.   You may visit from time to time but as God is my witness, this is not the kind of home in which to bring up a young girl.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Please don't do this Frank. She is happy here. I beg of you if you have a Christian bone in your body, you must see this is wrong.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>frank:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Don't lecture me, woman, on Christian values. I am aware of your affair with this radical Bradlaugh. My parishioners do nothing but gossip about you. You are an embarrassment to me, and even to your poor mother who is not at all well. no doubt he ill-health is hurried along by the stress of your godless behaviour. Come on, you men, get the child in the carriage and be gone.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The carriage leaves, with Annie sinking to her knees in the road. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INTerior: National REFORMER.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh enters the room.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh:             </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Good news Annie, we have won our appeal. We will not be going to prison after all. The Supreme Court has overturned the verdict.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>That is a relief Charles. But the book is now out of circulation. I cannot help but feel concern for all those women out there, worn out by giving birth. Now where will they get their information. They need special women's clinics where they can get advice. We have a small victory but alone it doesn't change things. I know, I will start writing a booklet on birth control that we can get into the hands of every married woman. And Charles, start organising some meetings. We have work to do!   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: PUBLIC HALL</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is on stage speaking to an audience mainly of women.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Women must take control of their lives, including their reproductive system. Bearing child after child wears us out. Each extra mouth to feed, means less for the others. Unless we women use birth control, we are little better than the animals in the farmyard producing litters for the farmers to sell. This booklet 'Population' gives you the knowledge to prevent unwanted pregnancies.You can buy a copy at the back of this hall. You can regain power over your own bodies. Ladies, we have a a long way to go. We must press forward. Not only should we have control over our bodies, but we must demand equal rights for women, the right to have an education for ourselves and all our children. the right to keep what we earn, and the right to vote for instance. Surely , we should have the right to choose the people who govern us.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>brADLAUGH:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh, she is going to far again...</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>How can we get laws to protect us, when it is the men who decide everything. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Bedroom in INDIA</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>narraTOR:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I continued to speak out for women's rights and promote birth control.Frank did not approve of my lifestyle but he did not prevent me from visiting both Digby and Mabel. However, it became obvious as time went by that my visits were upsetting them and I stopped going. But it wasn't long after my daughter was torn away, that I also took a path that would lose me that dearest of friends, Charles Bradlaugh, himself.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Conference hall </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is sitting there as the speakers talk about socialism. At the end of the meeting George Bernard Shaw comes up to talk to her. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Shaw:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I'm surprised to see you here, Mr Besant, I know Bradlaugh would not approve.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Charles is concerned we will have a French revolution here if you socialists get your way. However, I think the way forward is rapprochement between his ideas and those of the socialists. My publication 'Our Corner' is quite prepared to publish alternative ideas. I hear, Mr Shaw that you are struggling a little financially so perhaps I can help by offering you a regular column? And you can help me by explaining the evils of capitalism. Mr Shaw, Bernard, come to dinner on Saturday....    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: DINING ROOM at ANNIE's HOMe</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh arrives first. They hug showing they are close friends.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh Charles, it is so good to see you. We seem to see less of each other these days... </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BrADLAUGH:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I am busy preparing for the election. I am standing in Northampton as a Liberal so I am spending a lot of time away from London. But you are becoming famous! Up and down the country, you draw more crowds than I ever did. The National Secular Society owes you a great debt. How you find the time to publish all the magazines and write letter and articles? You are a powerhouse, little Annie.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I owe you a great deal, Charles. You have been my mentor... Another time, we might have been even more... but we have work to do. The world can be a cruel place and we have much to change.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie pulls apart, and becomes more focused. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Tonight I have invited some new friends to dinner. This includes Oscar Wilde, the well-known playwright and poet. And George Bernard Shaw. He is also a writer but struggling, all his novels have been rejected. I've been giving his commissions from my magazines to help him get by but he is very sensitive about his financial state so don't mention it.  And then there is ... well I will introduce them when they arrive. Please take drink    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The guests are seated for dinner. We see a group there for dinner. Charles Bradlaugh and GB Shaw are there. Eleanor Marx, a hippie of her time, daughter of Karl Marx. Dr Edward Aveling, a sleasy character. Oscar Wilde sweeps in late, dressed in velvet jacket and breeches.  A mix of sophisticated London society. Edward Aveling is talking....  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Aveling:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>It is , after all, the workers who create the wealth.They need to seize control. The capitalists will never give this up willingly, the workers must seize power..</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Sorry interrupt, Edward, everyone, may I introduce Oscar Wilde. Dr Edward Aveling, is my tutor at London University. Since last year some  Universities have at last accepted women, I have began to study for a Degree in Science.  Dr Aveling has one of the sharpest brains in the University.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>                         OSCAR: Sarcastically)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>             I have hear many of the female students are impressed with his sharper points. Do continue my dear fellow.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Aveling gives an irritated look at the foppish young man </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:                   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Over there is Charles Bradlaugh, soon to be an MP for Northampton, Elenora Marx - her father is Karl Marx, the author of Das Capital which is the talk of the socialists. I think you already know Bernard Shaw from the Fabian Society. Lord and Lady Durham, Walter and Popsie, who are very good friends of mine. Come and sit down, Oscar.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>AVELING</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>As I was saying, it is quite obvious that unless the working classes get control of the means of production they will always be exploited by the capitalist class.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Aveling, you know I have devoted my life to speaking up for the working man - and woman - but uprooting everything will leave the very people you are trying to help worse off. Just another set of bosses. Steady reform via the ballot box will accomplish what we all want. What say you Shaw? You are mixed up with this new socialist group, The Fabian Society. Are you going to stir up these poor creatures for revolution.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>A</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Shaw: (LIghtheartedly)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Karl Marx opened many eyes to the faults of capitalism. Eleanor what do you think your famous father would have to say about this group of privileged parasites sitting around this table discussing his theories?    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Elenor just shrugs and takes another drink. She is a sullen girl.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>shaw:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Charles, you will, everyone says, soon become a member of Parliament. It will be your chance to give voice to the workingmen. The Fabian Society  encourages reform not revolution. I'm not sure your fellow Liberal MPs will be supportive of your ideas. They are Liberal in name only. I don't support revolution, however, Aveling, these Marxists and Anarchists take life too seriously. Annie, you should come along to one of Fabian Society meetings. I think we can work together.        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>                       OSCAR (Passing the turkey dish)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>             I think you you would like a nice plump thigh, Bernard?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>    Shaw:(teasing)                   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Why thank you Oscar, actually I am a vegetarian - in food, of course.  I would guess a nice piece of rump, would be up your street?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie, shows her serious nature by not being amused at these two guests ribbing each other. The conversations about theatre, plays continues. Later on in the evening the conversations moves on to seances.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>    WALTER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Have any of you been to a seance? They are becoming the rage in London these days.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ELenor: (animated for a shorT time) </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh, I have. It was real spooky. I went to this house in Marylebone last week. We all sat around in the dark. The medium channelled someone's dead brother. She reveal things that could only have been known to the actual brother. The hairs on my arm stood up. Do you think we can really talk to the dead?    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>shaw:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Stuff and nonsense. I think most people around this table have already put God and angels behind us. Do you think we can accept spirits of the dead floating around wanting to chat to us.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                       O</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> oscar:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I hear there is a Russian women in town, Madame Blavatsky or some such name. She is a very popular medium. She wrote a book with a lot of mumbo jumbo from the East but so bloody obscure nobody actual reads it. I rather like the idea of there being more to our rather dull lives than we can readily see.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The conversations continue unheard by the audience. as the camera pulls back from the dinner party. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext; press reporters talk to Bradlaugh outside Parliament</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>reporter:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Congratulations of taking your seat in Parliament Mr Bradlaugh. I hear you were thrown out of the Chamber the first time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh:                </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>They wanted me to swear on the Bible making my oath. As a non-believer, this made no sense so I refused and they called in the bailiff to eject me. But finally, they have allowed me to affirm and I am due to make my maiden speech soon.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> REPORTER                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Your associate in the National Secular League, Mrs Besant, has joined the Fabian Society. Did you know? Are you also becoming a socialist?  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh: (looks shocked)                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>No I was not aware of that. Mrs Besant can choose her own path. I am certainly not becoming a socialist. I am opposed to this new movement. Good day, gentlemen, I need to go into the Chamber. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT./INT    Crowds listening to Annie</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>A collection of scenes showing Annie speaking on socialism, women's rights and Home Rule for Ireland.  VO  these scenes. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>NARRATOR:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Poor Charles, he was disappointed in my move to join the Fabian Society. But I felt we needed a political movement to move our agenda. We wanted the same things, but he thought he could instigate changes without major reform to society. He was now spending more time representing his electors we drifted apart. We remained good friends but I know I disappointed him then and again a few years later. Two events soon after I joined the Fabian Society thrust me further into the limelight.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: Shaw's Bedroom</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is in bed with Shaw. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Shaw:                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I think you first went to bed with me so I would propose you as a member of  the Fabian Society. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I did no such thing..... ( she sees Shaw laughing)...oh you and your jokes, Bernard. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Shaw:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, Annie, you take life so seriously... </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Shaw gets up, lights up a cigarette and looks at Annie cooly.              </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>shaw:                         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Have you thought any more about moving in with me Annie. I know you have left that scoundrel Avelon. He was a nasty piece of work. Owed money to everyone and played the field. Seriously,      I think we make a good team. My plays are attracting a lot of interest. They tell me one is to be put on in the West End theatres soon. You have inspired me dear Annie, as well as kept me fed and clothed for these past months. Let us live together! Love together! Laugh together! </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I told you I have conditions...</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>SHAW:                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh, and what are they? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie starts digging in her bag and brings out a long list list. She hands these to Shaw.                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Shaw: (visIbly taken aback)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>That is quite an extensive list...</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>He reads the list to himself. Annie watches his face as he reads. Fade out as he continues to read.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. WhitEhall and trafaLgar Square. LONDON</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Shaw are walking behind a crowd. We see banners for the March for the Unemployed. They bump into a man. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>SHAW:                </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie I'd like you to met William Stead. He writes many articles exposing injustices  and scandals. Are you covering this for one of the newspapers, William?   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>STEAD                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I am but I am not sure I can get close. The police are out in force. The organisers have been refused permission to hold the rally in Trafalagar Square by the Home Minster himself.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> ANNIE:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I know, I went to see him on behalf of the organisers but he refused to budge. But the people are angry and there are some radical elements who are determined to confront the police.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>    The trio walk to towards the Square. They are turned  back by the police but we hear shouting and screams. Shaw puts his arm around Annie protectively. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. police station</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie sweeps in demanding to see the prisoners. We see them locked up, some have bandages around bloody heads. A few are just young lads, others are gaunt looking working men. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                 </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>This is outrageous. These men have the right to protest. ( turns to the prisoners) I am making sure you all have legal counsel. We are already collecting money for a defense fund some of which which can be used for bail. I hope to get you all out of here by the end of the day. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh arrives. He is not happy. He takes her to one side. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Good morning. Annie I warned you and those socialist agitators about holding these rallies.  I'm now an MP, I have a voice. We can bring about reforms working with the Tories... these confrontations only hardens opinion. The public, the shopkeepers, Londoners, are inconvenienced and grow angry at these continued protests.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Talking is not putting food on the table. These men want jobs, they want pay. How long do they have to wait while you frock-coated gentleman have a gentle debate! Action is the only way to get change. Two men were killed and over one hundred injured by police using batons  trampled under the horse hooves. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The journalist and publisher Stead arrives</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh Hello Mr Stead, are you here to write up on the police brutality?      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>bradlaugh:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Good morning, Stead. Look I have to go now, Annie. You know my views on these socialists, take care. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>STEAD:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Actually, Mrs Besant, I came here hoping to catch you. Can we sit and have a cup of tea and talk? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. London tea house.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Stead and Annie sit drinking tea. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>  stead:              </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Besant, may I call you Annie? Er Annie, I'd like to make a proposal to you. As you know I have created new style of journalism and it has proved very successful for my publishing business. Some accuse me of sensationalism but I simply investigate deeply and print the results. The words may shock but people take notice. I want you, Annie to join me. You are not only an accomplished writer but a seasoned campaigner. You feel strongly about righting wrongs. I want you to join me in publishing a new magazine called "The Link".         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>But I am already writing for the National Secular magazine, helping Charles. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>STEAD:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, can't you see, you have moved on from the National Secular Society. You are now in the Fabian Society writing on social issues, not on narrow religious points. I still remain a Christian but this leads me to compassion for my fellow man. I want you to write and campaign on injustice in society. Right now, withing walking distance of this place, girls of 13 are being sold to men. I am campaigning to get the age of consent moved up to 15.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Why Mr Stead, William,I do believe you are even more passionate than me. I'm afraid Charles is rather disappointed in my embrace of socialism. But my sense of injustice was not recently awakened by the bloody events on Sunday. I have spoken out supporting Home rule for Ireland and even for India. I witnessed as a young girl the plight of  miners up North. Sir, I would be delighted to expose the horrors so many poor souls experience at the hand of the bosses and ruling classes.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>nArrAtor:                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Sadly Charles and I  moved further apart. He had got into Parliament but his health was flagging and he no longer had the energy for a fight. Bernard Shaw was frightened off by my detailed demands on what was required of him before we lived as man and wife. Looking back, I was probably far too serious for him. I eventually saw through Edward Aveling and ended that relationship. He then seduced poor Evelyn Marx, the daughter of Karl Marx. She eventually killed herself. Meanwhile I was working with William Stead on a new journal called The Link. It was was an article I wrote for Stead made me the darling of the trade union movement       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>inT. THE LINK OFFICES</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Stead comes in to where Annie is working.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>STEAD H:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, did you investigate the Bryant and May factory. The place where they make the matches. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I managed to get a couple of girls  to speak. Most of them are too scared to open their mouths. It is worse than I thought. Not only are the hours long 6.30 am to 6pm but working with the chemicals is damaging their health. The phosphorus is causing hair loss and also affecting the bones in the jaw. Their pretty young faces are distorted. The pay is so poor that the girl, many of them teenagers, survive on bread, butter and tea.  Here have a look at the draft and see what you think.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> STEAD:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Reads: "Do you know girls are made  to carry boxes on their heads until their hair is rubbed off and their young heads are bald at fifteen years of age? Country clergyman (he looks up at Annie knowing who she is digging at) ) with shares, draw down on your knee your fifteen-year-old daughter; pass your hand over the silky, clustering tresses, rejoice in the thick shiny tresses. Then like a ghastly vision, let there rise before you the pale, wan face of another man's fifteen-year-old daughter". Strong stuff, Annie. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Have you thought of a title for the article yet? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> Annie:                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Yes, I am putting in a bold headline across the top:  "White Slavery In London." </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie enters the office a few days later. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>                   STEAD:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Welcome back Annie. How did the lecture go in Birmingham? I must tell you some good news. Your article on the match girls has not only sold thousands of copies of our journal but is the talk of the town. The sad news is that Bryant and May management has sacked the two girls who spoke to you. They are trying to force other girls to say that what you have written is not true. They refused and now the bosses want to throw them all out.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Are they indeed. Well, we'll soon see about that. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie puts her coat on again and rushes out of the door. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>EXT: BRYANT &amp; MAY FACTORY GATES </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is seen encouraging hundreds of striking match girls.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>EXT HALL Annie is talking to the strike committee while supporters are preparing food and drink.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Supporter1:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Besant is a dynamo. Without her encouragement and fund-raising the girls might have given in. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We already live on the poverty line, we could not have held out for long. She raised money to help us hold out.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Supporter 2:           </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>And the newspapers are now more sympathetic. Donations are coming in. Charles Bradlaugh, the MP has raised the matter in Parliament. I hear the management is ready to talk.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text> INT Bryant &amp; mat boardroom </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and the strike leaders face the management.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>chairman of Directors:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Besant, as I have indicated, we have withdrawn any threats to the workers. Indeed the shareholders have asked me to to convey to you their regrets over this matter. And let me say personally, under pressure from my wife and daughter, I confess that I had not ensured the safety or looked after the welfare of our employees girls as I should. Mrs Besant, you have won. Tell me what I need to do.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>     Annie                 </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Workers are human beings, Mr Rathbone, like you and your board of directors. Like your own wife and daughter, they need to be well-fed and get enough rest. Like your own kin, you need to see they stay safe. We need the working hours reduced to .... Finally, we need a union to represent their interests to management in future.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>NARRATOR:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>It was a great victory. For the first time, non-skilled workers had a trade union. After that I was called upon up and down the country to help organise union representation for printers, dockers, gas workers, transport worker. I raised money and showed them how to organise  I even became a delegate to the Trade Union Congress. But my restless spirit led me away again...     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT link office </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Stead and Annie are talking</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:           </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>William, you know I wanted to move more into politics. I considered standing for election to London County Council but women are barred. However, I can get elected to the London School Board. I have heard the local churchmen are opposing my nomination because I am against compulsory religious education.       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> STEAD                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Go for it Annie. You know I do not share your views on God and religion but if your energies are focused on helping children, I know good will come out of it.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT School board meeting</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>                        ANNIE</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The children come from homes where they are not getting an adequate diet. Sometimes they come to school without any breakfast. How can we expect them to concentrate on lessons when they are hungry. The free school meals scheme will ensure every girl and boy in London will get at least one nourishing meal a day. I now think we should also consider setting up school medical services. This way we can catch diseases or medical conditions early.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Board member</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Besant, don't you think we rob these people of their self- reliance by offering all these free services. Also our budgets are not unlimited, you know.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>If parents don't earn enough to pay for food or a doctors care, it does not matter how self-reliant they want to be, they cannot provide these services. We have already reduced our costs by using the Board's strength in negotiating with suppliers, and incidentally insisting that they all obey union rules and pay their men fairly. These workers are also parents so a regular fair wage eventually benefits the children and us. And as I said, we cannot expect these children to focus on studies when they spend the day hungry. Let our school board lead the country by ensuring each London child has a meal provided by us. One nourishing meal as day, at least in their little stomachs. Do we all agree?       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The hands slowly go up and the Chairman passes the motion.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INt: Magazine OFFICE </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Stead and Annie on in discussion. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>STEAD:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You have often laughed at me for my Christian beliefs and even more so because I attend seances and believe the dead can communicate with the living. Annie, I know you  and deny the existence of God, but I have this book to review. It draws on many spiritual sources and some of it is beyond me.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>It is no so much that I do not believe in such things but I see no evidence of the sort of God who can help us. If he can. Then he must be very cruel to stand by and let so many suffer. There may be an unknowable spirit but that is very different than the Christian God. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>STEAD:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I know I can never win an argument with you, Annie. However, I do want to get a review of  "The Secret Doctrine.' The author is Madam Helena Blavatsky, you may have heard of her. It is not an easy book to understand and certainly clashes with my Christian beliefs but our readers should be given the opportunity to find out what its all about. Here take it home and read it.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie takes the thick volume and skims through it, there and then. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Annie's bedroom</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is in bed, still reading into night. She falls asleep a head full of dreams. Jesus and Buddha interchange, images of spiritual beings,monasteries in Tibet,  all whirl in her dream. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: The OFFICE OF The LINK jourNal</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie rushes excitedly in to Stead's office.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Charles, I have finished the book, yes 'The Secret Doctrine' But before I write the review I must meet the author. Do you know Madam Blavatsky? Can you set up an interview? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>sTEAD:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I haven't met her personally but I gather my good friend Burrows is on good terms. What I do know is that she is a Russian lady, apparently connected to the royal family.  You know it is quite the rage these days, both here and in America, to attend seances.  Madam Blavatsky is popular with society people. She is accomplished, I am told, at channeling spirits. What else... Some say she is a Russian spy ..oh yes she is one of the founders of the Theosophical Society. She and an American Colonel Olcott and another fellow set it up in the States some years back, now they are established here and India. From what I have read it is some kind of new religion. I think she might be worth investigating and exposing.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie (impatiently) </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Yes, yes, but can you fix up an appointment for me.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>STEAD:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I'll do that. Frankly I hope you will expose her for the charlatan I suspect she is. There have been some serious accusations about her cheating with letters purporting to come from another world. Your friend Bradlaugh has already written very negatively about her. Condemned her roundly.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>nARRATOR:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Little did I know that this meeting would have such a profound effect on my life.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Not only on my life but those around me whom I loved an admired.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The interview was duly set up. With expectation of meeting the author of such a spiritual book, meeting Helena Blavatsky for the first time was a tremendous shock. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>int. Blavatsky's drawing room </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The room was filled with exotic objects. The most dramatic was a stuffed ape. Madam Blavatsky was enormously fat and sitting in a large wheel chair. She is smoking. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>blavatsky:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Come in, my little radnaya. Don't be shy. Sit, Sit. I have heard a lot about you. You cause a lot of trouble, no? Ha Ha Haa. I like people who shake up the svolocks! </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:                         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I hear that you have not long been in London. Where is your home?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Blavatski:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I was on India, before that New York. The world is my home. But I love Paris, don't you Zaychik. Annie, you are so small, so slim. But I hear you draw many people to hear you speak about socialism and the absence of God. Maybe another time we discuss? Do you know this young man, George Bernard Shaw? I think one day he will be famous. He needs to eat some real food not all these cabbages and carrots. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Blavatski takes some chocolates off the stand next to her and offer Annie one. She refuses but Blavatsky consumes two or three.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BLAVATSKY:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>No? Too bad. Have you met Oscar Wilde. He came to a spiritual meeting I was leading. Likes the boys in tight breeches too much, I think ( roars with laughter). But I do plan to go to his show at Drury Lane Theatre on Friday. But Annie I know you have questions. I bet you have heard stories about me faking spirits. Ach! these svolocks. Please investigate. I don't mind.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                 </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I wanted to talk to you about your book...  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                       BLAVATSKy:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Another time, dear, I am more interested to learn about London society and your adventures in the riots.... </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The two continue to talk. It is not until Annie is about to leave that she fixes her guest with a penetrating gaze and says with emotion:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Blavatsky:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh my dear Mrs Besant, if only you would come among us.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie has conflicting emotions. Despite herself she is drawn to this strange woman and wants to kneel at her feet and kiss her hand but instead give a curt "Goodbye" As she leaves the house, we sense a change in her</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. bond street</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Two well-dressed women are gossiping. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>            </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Woman 1</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Have you heard the news about Annie Besant? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Women 2</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Let me guess. She's finally married Bradlaugh, now his wife has died? No, the affair with that playwright, Bernard Shaw is on again? She's in jail? Do tell me? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Woman 1</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>No. No, even more more surprising. She's gone back to God. Well, she has joined some Eastern religion.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Close up on Bradlaugh, speaks to camera .</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>BraDlaugh:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Yes, I heard she's joined the Theosophical Society run by that old Russian fraud. I wasn't happy that she had thrown her hand in with the socialists but at least we had a common cause. I am deeply disappointed. Her talent as a speaker is second to none and she could move a crowd. I'd hope she's eventually sit with me in Parliament. Yes, I am deeply disappointed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>INT</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>CU on George Bernard Shaw</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>SHAW:             </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh Annie, (chucking) you are always searching for something else. I wish you would learn to just have fun sometimes. I was angry with her when I first read her article titled "Why I became a Theosophist". She never discussed any of this with her friends. I feel Annie Besant, despite all her public speeches, never really threw off her religious upbringing. Her mind told her there was no God but her heart wanted there to be one. She is a remarkable woman. In fact I am basing a character in my play XXXX  on her. Of course, she will never recognise herself. She is always to busy for self-reflection.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. national secular society offices</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The committee is sitting around and voting               </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>chairman of NSS: (bangs gavel)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The motion is carried. Mrs Besant has been expelled from the National Secular Society. She is no longer a member.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. vicarage dining table. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The housekeeper brings in a letter on a tray which Frank Besant opens. His two children are sitting with him at the table eating a meal.                 </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>frank:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh, mmm, hrumpf. Children, your mother has really gone loony now.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: THEATRE Dressing room. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Oscar Wilde is getting made up for the stage.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>oscar:                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The Theosophical Society? Who would have believed it? That Russian witch must have put a spell on her. Frankly I cannot see their relationship lasting. Annie is so serious and,yes, pure while that fat old bag swears like a trooper, drinks and smokes like a chimney. For all that I rather like Helena Blavatsky. She is so outrageous. Even I cannot compete! But her and little Annie are so different...   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: The london home of Bradlaugh  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Bradlaugh's daughter Hypatia speaks to camera</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Hypatia:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I am probably not as surprised as others. She was very interested in spiritualism. When my sister Alice was dying, Annie wanted to be there as she died. She wanted to see the spirit leave the body. We had to be very firm to prevent her. It was rather creepy. Well she has done an about turn from secularism by joining up with this fashionable mystic and clairvoyant. It has upset my father who was very close to Mrs Besant - too close for my liking-  but I think it is a good thing Daddy severs contact with this woman.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXt. Northern town </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Two miners walking home after work</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Miner 1 </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Just hear that woman who came to speak at the Union rally has dropped out of the working class movement. Joined some Eastern religion.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>miner2: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Of aye, I remember her. Besant Annie Besant. she came up with Badlaugh, the MP. Bonnie wee lady. Could she speak, boy. But,yer know all this fancy posh people eventually revert to type. Sure as coal is black, eh.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. University Professors room</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Close up of Aveling.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>AVELING:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The woman has gone mad. She has stopped lecturing on Free-thought and socialism and turned her back on Darwinism. I hear she wants to destroy all copies of her booklet on birth control. She now preaches celibacy to stop births. Frankly, she was rather  cold in bed so I am not surprised at this suggestion. She prefers platonic friendships with her men friends.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Blavatsky:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I think it was preordained. Annie joined the Society just when I was tiring. Although I am only in my fifties, I can feel the time is coming when I must leave this world and move on to a new life. Annie has the energy to take us forward. Within a few months she has become like a daughter to me. She is a bit serious and often scolds me for bad language and smoking but I can feel the love between us growing.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT: Various HALLS. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie with Blavatsky, Annie speaking on platforms for the Theosophical Society  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                 </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>narRATOR:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I lost a lot of friends when I joined the Theosophical Society. It was particularly crushing to lose my relationship with Charles. Some thought Helena has hypnotised me or something. In a fact, she made no attempt to persuade me. Even freely admitted that he accusers thought she was a fraud.She handed me the results of the investigation they had made which pointed to sleight of hand yet I left her house after that first meeting, already ready to join her and the Theosophical Society. We soon gained the support of prominent poets and writers like W.B Yeats, G.K Chesterton. Even Oscar Wilde came to support some of our events. I threw myself into work for the Society but continued still to press for social change. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT lecture hall</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is addressing the audience. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>             </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Theosophy is a body of truths</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>, which form the basis of all religions, and cannot be claimed as the exclusive possession of any. It offers a philosophy which renders life intelligible, and which demonstrates the just and love that guided evolution. it puts death in its rightful place as a recurring incident in an endless life, opening the gateway of a fuller and more radiant existence. It restores to the world the Science and Spirit, teaching man to know the Spirit as himself, and the mind and body as his servants. It illuminates the Scriptures and doctrines of religions by unveiling their hidden meanings, and thus justifying them at the bar of intelligence, as they are ever justified in the eyes of intuition. REAL SPEECH </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext: Brookwood CEmentary and burial of Bradlaugh</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Three thousand mourners came to the funeral. There were no prayers. Many were Indians. In the crowd we see Gandhi, David Lloyd George and Annie dressed in black with a dark veil, stylish as ever.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>HYpatia:                </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh, she had to come. Even when he is dead she cannot leave Daddy alone. She broke his heart when she embraced all this Eastern mystic stuff... Oh Mr Lloyd George, my father would have been so happy to see the Liberal leader here today. Thank you for coming.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Lloyd George                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Well, we didn't always see eye to eye in the Commons but despite his radical views on religion, he was in my view a very Christian gentleman. Please, let me know, my dear, if there is anything I can do for you or the family....   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT, TRAin STATION</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>  The mourners are going home, waiting for the train. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>             </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Indian: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Poor Mr Bradlaugh. He died so young. Just 57. Wore out I think by his campaigning. Did you see, Gandhi, the number of us from the home country were at the funeral? Many of us called him the "MP for India" because he spoke out so strongly self-government for India.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Gandhi:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Yes, he and Mrs  Annie Besant have both been great supporters. I'm still studying for my law degree but I have managed to hear them speak in London. Oh look, what's going on over there...?  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>clergyman:                     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Without God there would be no morality in the world. We would be no better than the beasts in the fields.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ATHEIST:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Charles Bradlaugh did not believe in God. Yet did he murder or steal? You must have thought him a good person or you would not have joined the thousands at his funeral today.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>clergyman:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Aye, I'll grant you that. He was a fine man despite his perverse views. Maybe the spirit of God was within him even if he did not recognise it.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Atheist:                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Come on sir, he called the Bible the most immoral book imaginable. Full of slaughtering enemies and old prophets taking many wives....</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The camera returns to the two Indians observing the argument.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> INDIAN: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I wonder what they both think about us, dark skinned wallahs?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> Gandhi:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I don't think we are considered quite human. The British think it is God's will for them to rule over us in India. We are not Christians so we must be closer to the beasts! (Chuckles). One day when I return to India, I will make them see we are not only equal but perhaps better. Ahh, here the train coming now. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                        G</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext. Dockside.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie descends the gangway from a ship onto the dock. There are many people to welcome her back. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> Reporter:        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Welcome back to England, Mrs Besant. How did the American tour go? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>It went well. We had very big crowds in Boston and New York. The Theosophical Society is growing thanks to Mr Judge, who, as you know, was one of the founders. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Reporter:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Have you heard that Madame Blavatsky has recently died?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie: shocked and UPSET.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh, no. So soon after Charles. Two dear friends gone. No, I didn't hear about this. Oh my....I must hurry back to London, excuse me.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>InT. Annie's home</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>A group of theosophists are sitting around.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Brothers and sisters, it is now two years since our dear leader moved to a new plane. I must now go to India. Our President, Colonel Olcott is getting older and needs my help there. I also obligated to take a share of Madam Blavatsky's ashes to be scatted in the Ganges. I plan to leave in a few weeks. The Lodge here is in good hands, I know. Let us now move onto the items on the agenda for tonight's meeting...   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT: Boat drawing in to harbour at night</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is on deck with other passengers watching the lights.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Captain over tannoy                  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We will in a few moments be docking in Colombo, Ceylon. Will all passengers disembarking here, go to the starboard side of the boat. Your traveling trunks and  boxes will be unloaded from the hold and placed on the dockside. Please have your passports and other documentation ready. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie descends to the dockside. She is welcomed by Olcott, a distinguished American man with a beard.He is in his eighties.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Horse drawn cab</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The cab takes Annie and Olcott through the busy streets of Colombo. He is recognised often by passerby's.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Hotel </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Olcott are having dinner in Lavania Hotel, an sedate colonial hotel.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie                </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Thank you for traveling from India to meet me. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>olcott:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, it is so good to see you here. Both Ceylon, and India itself, can be a bit overwhelming on a first visit.   I spent many years here before moving to Adgar.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I hear you have establish many Buddhist schools in Ceylon.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Olcott:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Helena and I did a lot of research into the ancient texts. Sadly, Buddhism was declining. The locals were losing their culture and spiritual foundations. It was hard work at first but we have turned it around. There is much pride now. Educating the children so they understand their religion has been a large part of that. I am continuing to open new boys schools. We can visit one or two tomorrow when you have rested but first tell me about London. I haven't been back since the cremation...         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext. Sri Lankan countryside, visiting schools.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie accompanies the old man. Olcott is garlanded by students and staff. We see scenes of the Countryside and life of the locals. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Balcony at hill station bungalow</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Olcott:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You know Annie , Helena and I were very close. Good chums, nothing more. We actually had nicknames for each other. I was Maloney and she was Mulligan. Do you know how we met? I had left the army, served the Government as a civilian adviser, but I was interested in the occult. It was the rage in America at that time. I went down to a farm in Vermont to investigate three children who attracted spirit visitors. Madam Blavatsky was there, also drawn by curiosity, I think. We hit it off. We made a odd pair. She was already overweight, untidy and laughed like a man. I was a reserved and disciplined army man. A rather sad widower, I guess.  She had a great sense of humour and cheered me up. I followed her around while she was writing and holding seances. We eventually were drawn to India and felt this was a very spiritual land. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You know, Annie, she wrote to me about you. In her last few letters it was obvious she had grown fond of you but more than that... she wanted you to lead the Theosophical Society eventually.        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>But I cannot channel Koot Hoomi and the other adepts. I think I do sometimes get messages but it may be just in my head... I cannot get the guidance she does.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Olcott: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Hush, let me be open with you. Helena did have clairvoyant powers but she wasn't above inventing things if she felt that was what was needed to get attention or create faith. She admitted it. I think she even showed you documents claiming she cheated and dared you to disbelieve. She didn't take herself as seriously as others. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Many things she had invented early in her life but wasn't allowed to let it drop. But she saw that it was not Koot Hoomi and the others which were needed to take the Theosophical Society to the next stage but YOU my dear, that down- to-earth, practical dynamo. The Masters will guide you. You are a great organiser which is why you became her right-hand man. Channeling and seances are no longer fashionable. Theosophy has to adapt now we are in the 20th century. We need to show the world how close each religion really is. Science is opening up much that was unknown but we are to explore the deeper mysteries of the soul.        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie sits back and takes  drink, looks over at the valley.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Olcott:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We will soon leave for India and Madras. Once you settle in the headquarters in Adgya, you will be able to plan how we can go forward. This country is remarkable for the different religions living side by side. There is a lot of poverty and disease but spirituality flows in the veins of every man women and child in this beautiful land.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext. Street scenes in INDIA</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Crowds are waiting to greet Annie and Olcott. There are banners welcoming Annie Besant as they ride in an open car towards the Theosophical Society headquarter. Many rush to kiss her hand.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>How do they know my name? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>OLcott:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>The Indians are great readers.  They have been reading your teachings and embraced them. They are also aware of your demands from the platform in England and in the British Times newspaper calling for Home Rule in India. You are a heroine!    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>annie: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Henry, I want to stay out of politics now I am here. The socialist and Marxists turned on me because of Theosophy. I tried for a few years to continue my social activism but I was forced out of all the organisations. Dear Charles still remained a friend but he no longer shared his strategies or, indeed, any intimacies. Now he has passed on. I can see your efforts have been towards education and I would like work with you on this. Did you know I sat on the London School Board for many years. Actually I only resigned when I knew I was coming to India.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT hall in ENGLAND </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Two members of the audience are talking while waiting for Annie to appear.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                 </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>AUDIENCE 1</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Well she can certainly still attract a crowd despite hiding away in India for more than a year. I heard she has been on speaking tours in the USA and Australia. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Audience 2:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I hear she has become a Hindu.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Audience 1:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>A what...?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Audience 2:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Hindu. You know one of those religions for the natives out there in India. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Audience1:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Who is that sitting on stage. The man with the beard. Is that Colonel Olcott?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>  AuDience2                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh no. Poor Olcott died with Mrs Besant at his side. That fellow is Charles Leadbeater. Apparently Mrs Besant thinks the world of him but most of the members think he is creepy. There are rumours that he is a little too friendly to the young boys he teaches.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> Audience1                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Well, I never, he looks so respectable sitting up there.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The organiser comes on stage.       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>organiser:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>As those of you who are members are aware we lost one of our founders, and the President of the Theosophical Society,  Henry Steel Olcott recently. He and Madam Blavatsky established our  society headquarters in India. The Colonel  is sorely missed but the Masters decided his help was needed on a higher plane. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>It was the dying wish by our former president that he was succeeded by someone who has given so much to our Society. His wish, which been confirmed by votes from the London Committee and other branches around the world, that Annie Besant, should become the new President on this special day in 1907. May I present the new President of the Theosophical Society.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie walks on stage. She is dressed in Indian costume quite a contrast from her very fashionable English dress in earlier times. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Brothers and Sisters, distinguished guests, ladies and gentlemen. I realise the heavy responsibility this honour of president has bestowed on my. Firstly, I am following two of the great figures of the 19th century, HPB, Madam Blavatski, and Colonel Olcott. They have pulled aside the veils of our higher purpose. They have been our guides in this world, a light for us to follow the path the hidden Masters have set for us. The Theosophical Society has enjoyed a popularity few expected. I believe the world is ready for us...    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>ANNIE' OFFICE in LONDON</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and several senior members of TS stand around  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Committee member 1                     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>This has become a scandal that threatens our very existence. Our German and American branches are threatening to break away. You have been warned about Charles Leadbeater before. This time is is more serious. The complaint is from one of our long term supporter and benefactor and it is his own children who have been encouraged in inappropriate behaviour by this man entrusted to teach them.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>These are just allegations. Charles Leadbeater has contributed so much to Theosophy. I refuse to believe he has done such a thing. He is outside now and we can ask him.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>CommitteE member 2:                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, I know you are fond of the man, but we have no choice. He has to resign or we have to vote him out. It will come to a choice between TS and him.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Very well, ask him to come in. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The door is opened at Leadbeater is asked to come in.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>             </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Charles please come in. We have discussed the allegations. I am shocked and saddened to hear them. But I want to hear your side before we go further. Did you encourage these boys to .... er indulge in touching their.. er penises?   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>LEADBEATER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You mean masturbate. Yes, I did.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The committee give shocked looks</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>LeaDBEATER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>These are healthy young boys at puberty. It is a natural at that age. I wanted them to overcome their guilt and worries that come from foolish tales of masturbation creating blindness.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Charles, you may feel this is right but this will damage the Society if it gets out. I am sorry, but you either resign or we have to cancel your membership. It grieves me to give this ultimatum but we have no choice.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Leadbeater: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Very well, you know I hold you in the highest esteem and I would not like to hurt the Society in anyway. I did what I felt was right. Maybe I am too progressive for many.  I will write a resignation letter tonight. Good day to you all.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The committee looks relieved but Annie does not look happy. She looks sad,</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. TS headquarters INdia</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>A bearded man is watching two young Indian boys splashing about in the water of the lake. We see it is Charles Leadbeater. After some time he goes over to talk to them. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT TS headquarters</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Leadbeater                     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, do you remember HPB telling us to expect a world leader to appear. Well I think he is here. I have met him today in our grounds. I saw these two boys today and I think they were sent to us by the Masters.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>What boys, where? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>LeadBEATER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>They were bathing in the lake. Their father works for us as a gardener.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:                         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>(Sighs) I hope this isn't going to be a repeat of the nonsense which went on in London. Much against protests of others I have let you back into the Society but there must be no repetition of ... well ... you know. Take me to meet them tomorrow. What are their names? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>leadBEATER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Jiddu Krishnamurti and his brother Nitya. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT. Grounds of TS </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see Annie and Leadbeater talking to the two boys. They look like typical local boys. Nitya is more animated while Krishnamurti is quieter. They walk together while Annie asks questions. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Leadbeater leave the boys and walk back to the house together. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Leadbeater: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Well, what do you think? Is one of them the new World leader for whom we are waiting. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I don't know, Charles, I will make contact  with the Masters this evening. I hope they will guide us.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The boys are running around, laughing, not knowing the change fate has in store for them. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Int TS ANNIE'S ROOMS</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is having breakfast. Leadbeater comes in.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>LeADBEATER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Good morning, Annie, do you have any news? Is one of these boys the one we have been waiting for? </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I had to wait a long time but the message came through. Yes the World Teacher we are expecting is close. The identity was not fully revealed so which boy, I cannot say. You realise our role is to groom him and develop his powers. That must be our prime purpose from now on.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>LeadBEATER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I will talk to their father. I have seen him around. I am sure he will be only too glad to have his sons educated at our expense.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Please make sure proper papers are drawn up. We need to have control of their education, environment and spiritual development. The father must be made clear on this. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>narrator:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I still remember my first sight of those two boys. Nitka seemed to be more intelligent and lively than his brother Jiddu, but Charles read their auras and was convinced the quiet boy was the one. However, we agreed to bring them both up together. It was fascinating to see how these raw young boys developed into sophisticated young men. Krishnamurti became like a son to me. I could not foresee that he would in the end cause my most serious heartbreak.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. sophisticated Party in UK house</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Krishnamurti in his early twenties, dressed in western clothes, is mixing with the guests, quite at home.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>party girl1                  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oooh, Jiddi Krishnamurti, so are you going up to Oxford?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>KRiShnamurti: </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>No, 'fraid not. Failed the entrance exam again. Mother Besant was quite upset with me. I really am not the academic type.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>party girl1</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Oh, Jiddu, what will become of you? I'm sure there are plenty of girls here who would love to marry you and keep you in nice suits like this one. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>krisHnamurti:                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I'm afraid they have big plans for me in India. I do not have much choice. Mother Besant says the hidden masters have already set out my path. Ugh. Never mind, lets not talk of this, now. Shall we dance?  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INt. TS headquarters INdia</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is surrounded by Indian guests.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:          </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>My friends, as you know I have spent many years helping to found schools and colleges. Education is a key to a better life for these children. I have also spoken out on rights for Indian women - not always gaining me popularity from some men! I have adopted Hinduism as my religion, encourage an appreciation of the literature and arts of India. I have wanted to restore a pride in the greatness of India. Not forever thinking that foreign powers are superior.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>             </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>When I came here in 1893, I said I would not get involved in politics. But it is becoming increasingly clear to me that unless political action is taken, India's silk and cotton trade will be lost to the colonial masters. I see British textiles in our markets, not India cloth. You Indians are barred from certain jobs and organisations by the British. Years, back back in London, I spoke of the need to give India home rule. I believe it is now time for Indians to push for this change. If you are to feel the pride in your nation then you must govern yourselves. Your fight is my fight. Let us make 1913, a year that marks the beginning of the struggle. Who can we get in to work with us. Can we come together on this, across politics, religions and castes?   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. hall</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie Besant is on stage giving a rousing speech. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>....the colonial power is crushing the life out of the people. Their rule is one of broken promises. They are ignoring the needs of the people. If Britain still wants the benefits of India, his majesty needs to give more power in how this country is run. Your culture and religion is undermined by the British and your economy wrecked by their demands. India must become self-governing. A partner to the British crown , not a servant. Loyal subjects of King Edward but free citizens in their own country with Indians making decisions for Indians.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. TS OFFICE London</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Group of Theosophists are discussing events in India</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>TS member 1:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I'm concerned about the news from  India. I think our President is going too far. The society should not be getting mixed up in politics.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>TS Member 2                         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I agree, what has Indian Home Rule got to do with our objectives, our philosophy? What do you think, Sir Alfred?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>SIR Alfred:                         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie has always been a bit headstrong, jumps right in without thinking.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> TS MEMBER 3:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>To be fair, up to now she has kept quiet and focused on education. her peace. Maybe this latest enthusiasm will blow over.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>inT. Foreign secretaries office</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Minister and his private secretary are discussing situation  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>  minister:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I'm not happy , Reginald, with this Besant woman stirring up unrest in India. Particularly when we could find ourselves in a war in Europe if this Hungarian clash with the Serbs  doesn't quieten down.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>REGInald:                         </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Some of us can remember her from trade union days in London. She's a real firebrand. Mixed up with the Marxists then. I thought after she got caught up in this Eastern religion stuff, she would disappear into an ashram or something. Obviously not. Reports from our intelligence officers say she recently founded the All India Home Rule League and it's getting traction.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>minister:                   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Get in touch with our chappie out there and warn him. If war breaks out and we are involved then she needs to be shut up promptly. We need India to be in a peaceful state. We might need to recruit some of natives for the army and we certainly are going to want trade to continue uninterrupted. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>int. British colonial Office in Bombay  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is meeting with the Vice Roy</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>VICEROY:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Besant, I have given you the courtesy of arranging this meeting to tell you personally, his Majesties governments position. War has now been officially declared between Great Britain and its allies and the Austria-Hungarian Empire. You may not feel the effects here but our young men are dying on the battlefield. Your calls for a revolution here cannot, and will not be ignored.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>My dear young man, I fully support my home country in this unfortunate war but that will not stop me continuing my demand for Home Rule for the Indians. We must let the Indians have a say in government. I must and will continue to campaign or their behalf.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>VICEROY:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Then you leave me with no choice. You will either be repatriated back to England or you will be interned here until the European conflict ends.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I have no intention of returning to England,young man. Let me make that clear. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Very well. In view of your age and position, I will refrain from locking you up in jail. Please return home and we will make arrangements. I assure you it will be as comfortable as possible. Good day to you, Mam. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>EXT OOTACAMUND</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie ( now 70) draws up in a car with two British solders and a local government officer in attendance. The surroundings are beautiful, this is highland cool country. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>local Government OFFICIAL:                       </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Here we are Mrs Besant. I am sorry we have to do this.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Hrmm!</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>local Government OFFIciAL:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>You must remain here. There is a servant to take care of you and these two soldiers will not only make sure you stay put but will protect you. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>ANNIE:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Young man, I need no protection from the Indians. And no matter how beautiful the surroundings, you have taken away my freedom. You have forcibly silenced my voice. Roses round the door do not compensate for this unfair internment!    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT: Major city</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Crowds throng the streets demanding the release of Annie Besant. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Annie's Interment cottage, a month later</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie answers a knock on the door. The local official is back  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>local Government OFFICIAL:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Mrs Besant, I have papers for your release. I am to escort you on the first part of your journey home.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie                        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Is the war over , after just a few month?</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text> </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>local Government OFFIciAL:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>No Mam, the war continues. More and more men are dying. I cannot tell you why you have been released. Please pack. I will wait in the car.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>             </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext. Streets in Madras full of crowds. ANNIE is greeted like a film star.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>int. huge hall</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The hall is full of delegates to 1917 Indian National Congress. Chairman bangs gavel.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text> Chairman of meeting:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Please be quiet, quiet now. I now have the result of the election of President . I am pleased to announce that the President of our Indian National Congress is Mrs Annie Besant! </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Cheers erupt. We are conscious of this tiny old lady making her way to the podium. She stands smiling  amid deafening cheers. We see seated in the audience Gandhi. At this time he still wears western clothes. Later he approaches Annie.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Why Mr Gandhi, I am pleased to see you here. I remember meeting you in London with Madam Blavatsky. You were still studying law as I recall. I congratulate you on your success on South Africa in forming the Natal Indian Congress and the work you have done for civil rights. When did you return? What are you plans now you are back in India ?  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>gandhi:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Yes, I returned in 1915 but decided to be quiet for a year or so until I understood what was going on. I have followed your various campaigns for a long time. In fact, I had a picture of you in my Capetown office when I was still doing legal work. Of course, I fully support Home Rule for India. But I am afraid I seek full independence from Britain. We cannot be part of the Empire or we will never be free. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I'm afraid the British crown will not let India go without a fight. I want self-government but I do not want to see bloodshed or the people suffer more deprivation.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>gandhi:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I believe we can have a campaign of non-violent resistance and achieve the goal. But the time for talking and negotiating is over. Your efforts are much appreciated but it is time we Indians took the lead.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is dragged away by supporters, leaving Gandhi looking thoughtful.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT: Annie is seen with Gandhi but it becomes obvious she is second to him. He is now seen wearing the dhoti  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>narrator:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I did fully appreciate it at the time but that day was the last time I took centre stage. As a white woman, to be elected as President of the Indian National Congress, was quite a feat. But age was catching up with me. Mr Gandhi was drawing the crowds as the year ended and he became the leader of the Independence movement. We worked together at times but I feared his actions wold lead to violence... and they did. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INTERIoRS and Exterior of annie lecturing in various countries for the THeosophical society.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I continued to travel lecturing in the USA, Australia England and in my chosen home India. Charles Leadbeater continued to cause problems and we packed him off to Australia. Krishnamurti and I stayed together in California.        </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT: garden at TS Centre IN CALIFORNIA</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Where is Jiddu? I haven't seen him this morning</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Emily lutyens:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>He is in his room. He had another of his attacks. He is in great pain at these times</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I think it shows the Kundalini is awaking in him. The Divine Spirit is descending once more onto a Man. Jiddu...Krishnamurti will emerge as the World Teacher.    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>EMIly lutyens:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Sometimes, Annie, I think you expect too much of him. He is a simple young man who hates pomp and ceremony. He wrote to me that he was very uncomfortable during the trip to Australia where you took him to Charles Leadbeater. He and Wedgewood have ordained themselves as Bishops of the Liberal Catholic Church. He was very unhappy seeing all the gowns and colourful ceremonies. And you must be careful, yourself, the Theosophists are very much against this association of their President and this rebel Church. And I hear Leadbeater is also facing more accusations of behaving inappropriately  with young boys. Annie, as your friend, I ask you not to push Jiddu. If you are right, he will come to it in his own time. We need to worry about these painful attacks, maybe he needs to see a doctor. His brother Nitya's lungs are getting worse, I fear. The dry air here is helping but I fear he will not be long on this plane.     </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Charles is a good and dedicated man. His moves are guided by the Masters. I don't wish to hear any more nonsense about him. I know Jiddu is destined to lead  mankind spiritually, I just get a little impatient with him. He seems so dreamy at times, Emily, you know I am a person of action. I set up the Order of the Star as his own movement. He talks so beautifully to the young men and women who all adore him, but he seems unwilling to assume the mantle of leadership. Anyway, help me up and let me go and see the poor boy. How is that husband of yours? I see the name Edwin Lutyens often cited as the finest architect alive today. The Indian nation will remember him with gratitude  this current project in creating whole city..what's it called..er New Delhi.          </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>INT: Emily's room at the TS California. She writes a letter to her husband, the architect Edwin Lutyens.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Emily lutyens:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>My dear Teddy, I do hope you project for the Vice Royal's home and the plans for the new city in India are progressing well. I am sure you have designed a legacy for yourself and India.  I am proud to have such a talented husband. Annie is proving stubborn as usual. She will hear no bad word about that dreadful man Leadbeater. He is facing criminal investigations now and I can tell you many of the senior Theosophists are angry and feel this will reflect badly on the Society. Annie is such a bad judge of men. Look at that seducer Aveling in London, who borrowed money from everyone. Bernard Shaw just played with her and then later attacked her. As you know I am very close to Jiddu Krishnamurti, almost the mother  he never had, and he confides in me. He was disgusted with what he saw in Australia and I fear he is already slowly moving away from this role Annie sees for him. I am torn. It will break her heart but I also see a young man who has had his life mapped our by other and not allowed to develop normally. He does what he is told but I fear a break will come in not too many years. Currently he is worried about his brother who is dying of tuberculosis. This stress and his denial of the role of World Leader is behind his frequent painful attacks that force him to go to bed. I do my best, to keep them both happy but it wears me out sometimes. Do take care of your health on these frequent visits to India. I am afraid it is all too easy to catch disease there.  I look forward to our reunion, all my love, Emily.          </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>EXT: Order of the Star camp in Holland 1929. 3,000 Expectant young people are seated on the grass waiting for the World leader Krishnamurti to address them. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>KRiShnamurti:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We are going to discuss this morning this morning the dissolution of the Order of the Star of the East. Many people will be delighted, others will be rather sad. It is a question neither for rejoicing  nor for sadness, because it is inevitable ....</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>FULL SPEECH Show audience in tears and shocked.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Again you have the idea that only certain people hold the key to the Kingdom of Happiness. No one holds it. No one has the authority to hold that key. That key is your own self, and in the development and the purification and in the incorruptibility of that self alone is the Kingdom of Eternity. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>MORE SPEECH....  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>So these are some of the reasons why, after careful consideration over two years, I have made this decision. It is not a momentary impulse. I have not been persuaded to it by anyone. I am not persuaded in such things. For two years I have been thinking about this, slowly, carefully, patiently, and I have now decided to disband the Order, as I happen to be its Head. You can form other organisations and expect someone else. With that I am not concerned, nor with creating new cages, new decoration for those cages. My only concern is to set men absolutely, unconditionally free.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>Ext: Kalang Airport 1929( actually opens 7 years later)</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie arrives to a welcoming crowd with Charles Leadbeater to visit the Singapore Lodge of the Theosophical society. Both are now very old.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>EXT: STREET IN SINGAPORE</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Leadbeater are in a taxi. They look out and see the bustling life in this city.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>leadbeater:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, can you feel the energy in this place. We have passed Temples, Churches and Mosques. All the races and religions are mixing here. Singapore points to the future. This place will grow into a place of importance,  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>I just hope they do not neglect the spiritual side in their anxiety to make a fortune. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. Theosophical Society Singapore</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie and Leadbeater meet the members and look at the photos on the wall.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:                    </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Look Charles at the photograph. It show dear Colonel Olcott with BP de Silva, the jeweler. he was the first president. Look at the date, 1889, it was the same year I met Helena Blavatsky in London. Oh my, it seems so long ago so much has happened. It has been an uphill struggle... </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>          LEADBEATER:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>We are not in good spirits,Annie,at this time. I think we are both shocked and saddened by the defection of Krishnamurti earlier in the year.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>Annie:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>How could we have gotten it so wrong, Charles. Have we been fooling ourselves with these messages from the Masters? Did we want so desperately to welcome a new Messiah, that we imagined it all? I am so tired. I do not feel I can fight any more. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>leadbeater:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>Annie, don't distress yourself. Jiddu still loves you like a mother. Despite his strict training under me, he is still fond of me. Look at all these people here. They believe in you and the Theosophical Society. You found the same on your visit to Australia and New Zealand. Look they are waiting for us. Time for us to take centre stage! Come, Annie.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>The two old timers walk in front of the applauding audience. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Scene Heading"/>
      <text>INT. ANNIE'S HOME IN INDIA</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Annie is in bed. There are many people outside the door waiting to say farewells.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Character"/>
      <text>narRATOR:</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Dialogue"/>
      <text>It was a blow to me when Krishnamurti renounced his role. Did I misread the Masters? Did Leadbeater do anything to him when younger? Jiddu denies this and still speaks fondly of him. Krishna still loves me, I can see,  but he is determined to go his own way. I am disappointed, of course. but as I get older, I am more accepting. Did I make a mistake, thinking he was the chosen one, the new World Leader?.... But my  own children, dear Mabel joined my Society and Digby has grown closer to me in recent years, This has been a great comfort.  A fall down the stairs in my office ended my traveling days. And I find it harder to remember my speeches. Its funny how the early years remain fresh in the mind. I once wrote that on my tombstone I would like the words "She sought after the truth". Well, as a Hindu I wish to be cremated and there will be no grave. You know, in my reincarnation, I hope I can find more peace. This life was a struggle and I was always seeking more. Bernard Shaw always told me I took life too seriously. I think maybe he was right. I didn't find the Truth but I hope I have been useful...I feel I have led many lives while still in this one mortal body.      </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>EXT: Funeral Pyre</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>We see the flames as Annie's body is burned. Huge crowds surrounded the body.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>EXT: The quiet of the Ganges in the early morning. Her followers pour her ashes in the water.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>CREDITS</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>GANDHI began to dress in simple white dhobi and started his campaign. As Annie Besant feared it did lead to bloodshed but eventually in 1947 India won complete independence. He remained respectful of Annie despite their differences.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>KRISHNAMURTI eventually became a famous and highly- regarded spiritual leader, author and philosopher. He died in 1986. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>CHARLES LEADBEATER died a year after Annie. He started the Anglo Catholic Church in Australia. Once again reports of sexual misconduct with young boys surfaced but he was never charged. </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>GEORGE BERNARD SHAW went from a penniless writer to a famous playwright creating plays such as St. Joan, and Pygmalion, which was turned into the hit musical My Fair Lady. He remained a socialist and wrote many books and pamphlets.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>OSCAR WILDE. Wrote many plays such as The Importance of Being Ernest and Lady Windermere's Fan and the novel The Picture of Dorian Gray. Despite his fame and brilliance was thrown in jail for a homosexual relationship and emerged a broken and poor man dying in Paris soon after in 1900.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>ROBERT STEAD became famous and is considered the father of the tabloid newspapers and investigative journalism. He drowned in the Titanic sinking after heroically helping others to safety.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Hypatia Bradlaugh and Mabel Besant both continued the work of their respective parents becoming activists for their causes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>THE THEOSOPHICAL SOCIETY remains an active world-wide organisation although in numbers  has shrunk. The headquarters remain in Adyar, India.   </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>Rev. Frank Besant remained in Sisley until his death in 1917, spending his leisure time collecting parish history. He is buried in St Margaret's Church graveyard.  </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>ANNIE BESANT is still revered in India. There are several street named after her. She had written and spoken eloquently on independent governance for the India while still in London and was a major force in the movement in India years before Gandhi came on the scene. She founded many schools, supported women's rights and promoted both Hinduism and Buddhism, urging Indians to take a pride in their culture. In the West, however, she is largely forgotten. Other people have instead become associated with her pioneering efforts in women's rights, birth control, sex education. Her speeches and campaigns on Home Rule for Ireland and Trade Unions and her success in introducing free school meals and medical services for pupils are not remembered. Had Annie Besant gone into English politics, she would have probably been the first woman Cabinet Minister. She also found time to become a Freemason in Europe becoming the Grand Master in Co-masonry in England. A fine orator, an indomitable organiser and a truly remarkable woman.              </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text>THE MANY LIVES OF ANNIE BESANT</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Action"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
  </paragraphs>
  <titlepage>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para bookmark="Title">
      <style basestylename="Normal Text" align="center"/>
      <text underline="1">ANNIE</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text" align="center"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text" align="center"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text" align="center"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text" align="center"/>
      <text>Written by</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text" align="center"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para bookmark="Author">
      <style basestylename="Normal Text" align="center"/>
      <text>Allein Moore</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para bookmark="Copyright">
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text>Copyright (c) 2020</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para bookmark="Draft">
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text>Draft
information</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text></text>
    </para>
    <para bookmark="Contact">
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text>alleinwrites@gmail.com</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <style basestylename="Normal Text"/>
      <text>+60 125642420</text>
    </para>
  </titlepage>
  <spelling language="en_US">
    <user_dictionary/>
  </spelling>
  <lists>
    <characters>
      <character name="Squire Trevelyn:"/>
      <character name="Annie"/>
      <character name="Squire Trevelyn - embarassed:"/>
      <character name="annie:"/>
      <character name="Annie:I hope you will come to Church on Sunday and listen to my husband's sermon. It may help purge these lustful thoughts from your mind!"/>
      <character name="Narrator"/>
      <character name="Frank:"/>
      <character name="HOUSEKEEPER/SECRETARY"/>
      <character name="BISHOP"/>
      <character name="MOTHER"/>
      <character name="FRANK"/>
      <character name="MOTHER:"/>
      <character name="MINER:"/>
      <character name="ROBERTS"/>
      <character name="Prosecutor"/>
      <character name="JUDGE:"/>
      <character name="MABEL:"/>
      <character name="BRADLAUGH:"/>
      <character name="BrADLAUGH"/>
      <character name="BRadlaugh:( hesitatingly)"/>
      <character name="Annie: Laughing"/>
      <character name="Co worker 1"/>
      <character name="co-worker 2"/>
      <character name="Prosecutor:"/>
      <character name="Manchester Martyrs:"/>
      <character name="Roberts:"/>
      <character name="Man and Crowd:"/>
      <character name="Int. The original church"/>
      <character name="Miss Marryat:"/>
      <character name="FRIEND:"/>
      <character name="Miss marryot:"/>
      <character name="NARRATOR:"/>
      <character name="mary:"/>
      <character name="foreman:"/>
      <character name="JUDGE"/>
      <character name="SHAW:"/>
      <character name="Annie:(smiling)"/>
      <character name="AVELING"/>
      <character name="Guest 1:"/>
      <character name="GUEST 2:"/>
      <character name="ELenor:"/>
      <character name="shaw                        Shaw:"/>
      <character name="oscar:"/>
      <character name="reporter:"/>
      <character name="REPORTER"/>
      <character name="STEAD"/>
      <character name="STEAD:"/>
      <character name="Supporter 2:"/>
      <character name="chairman of Directors:\Managing director"/>
      <character name="Board member"/>
      <character name="blavatsky:"/>
      <character name="Blavatski:"/>
      <character name="Woman 1"/>
      <character name="Women 2"/>
      <character name="chairman of NSS:"/>
      <character name="Hypatia:"/>
      <character name="Miner 1"/>
      <character name="miner2:"/>
      <character name="AVELING:"/>
      <character name="Annie: shocked"/>
      <character name="Captain over tannoy"/>
      <character name="olcott:"/>
      <character name="Olcott                O"/>
      <character name="OLCOTT"/>
      <character name="AUDIENCE 1"/>
      <character name="Audience 2:"/>
      <character name="Audience 1:"/>
      <character name="organiser:"/>
      <character name="Audience1:"/>
      <character name="Ausience2"/>
      <character name="Audience1"/>
      <character name="Committee member 1"/>
      <character name="CommitteE member 2:"/>
      <character name="LEADBEATER:"/>
      <character name="Leadbeater"/>
      <character name="party girl1"/>
      <character name="KRiShnamurti:"/>
      <character name="TS member 1:"/>
      <character name="TS Member 2"/>
      <character name="SIR Alfred:"/>
      <character name="TS MEMBER:"/>
      <character name="minister:"/>
      <character name="REGEnald"/>
      <character name="REGInald"/>
      <character name="REGInald:"/>
      <character name="VICEROY:"/>
      <character name="local Government OFFIAL:"/>
      <character name="Chairman of meeting:"/>
      <character name="gandhi:"/>
      <character name="gadhi:"/>
      <character name="Emily lutyens:"/>
      <character name="Mother: narrator"/>
      <character name="AMY:"/>
      <character name="William:"/>
      <character name="Annie:(Pulls a face)"/>
      <character name="Police SergeanT:"/>
      <character name="Prisoner"/>
      <character name="Prosner 2"/>
      <character name="RESCUER:"/>
      <character name="police constable:"/>
      <character name="Police commissioner"/>
      <character name="Guard:"/>
      <character name="LADY:"/>
      <character name="Prison Guard"/>
      <character name="Annie: close to tears"/>
      <character name="miss marryat:                      MI"/>
      <character name="BISHOP:"/>
      <character name="Bradlaugh:                      B"/>
      <character name="bradlaugh                 B"/>
      <character name="Hypendia:"/>
      <character name="Daughter 2"/>
      <character name="brandlaugh:"/>
      <character name="Lloyd George"/>
      <character name="Indian:"/>
      <character name="clergyman:"/>
      <character name="ATHEIST:"/>
      <character name="Gandhi                        G"/>
      <character name="ANNE:"/>
      <character name="L"/>
    </characters>
    <locations>
      <location name="SYNOPSIS"/>
      <location name="OPENING TITLES"/>
      <location name="EX Cutback to the young woman galloping across the countryside. She has been observed by a well-dressed gentleman also on horseback who follows her into the woods. By the time he catches up, the lady is now fully dressed and her horse is grazing."/>
      <location name="Cut to exterior of a grand country house, home of the Bishop. Annie enters the house"/>
      <location name="INT Annie enters the house led by the Bishops'housekeeper"/>
      <location name="Interior. We see the Bishop genially greet her as she enters HIS OFFICE. We view them both through the glAss in the door. We cannot heAR the Conversation disTinctly but as the discussion evoLves the bishop can be seen getting more and more angry. THE DOOR IS EVENUALLY THROWN OPEN."/>
      <location name="ANNIE HURRIES DOWN THE DRIVE. IT IS OBVIOUS THAT SHE IS NOT COWED BY THE RECENT EXCHANGE. THE SHOCKED BISHOP LOOKS OUT OF HIS WINDOW AS SHE LEAVES."/>
      <location name="INTERIOR Of run down London church"/>
      <location name="OUTSIDE THE CHURCH"/>
      <location name="VARIOUS SCENES"/>
      <location name="RAILWAY STATION"/>
      <location name="ANNIES HOME"/>
      <location name="William Roberts' OFFICES"/>
      <location name="COURTROOM"/>
      <location name="Street scene."/>
      <location name="COURT"/>
      <location name="COURT SCENE"/>
      <location name="INT: BEDROOM"/>
      <location name="INt: hastings church"/>
      <location name="Annie visits the parishioners. Sits by the bedside as a woman loses her baby, attends funeral with baby casket."/>
      <location name="EXT/INT SIBSEY CHURCH"/>
      <location name="CHURCH on other days"/>
      <location name="Church"/>
      <location name="train carriage"/>
      <location name="posh house in londom"/>
      <location name="Ext: Outside HALL. We see FREETHINKERS POSTER with Bradlaugh as speaker."/>
      <location name="Packed hall.ON stage is the speaker charles Bradlaugh. He is a TALL handsome man and a FINE ORATOR."/>
      <location name="EXT: Streets of London"/>
      <location name="Bradlaugh's small living room. It is full of books and rather untidy."/>
      <location name="Int: national Reformer offices"/>
      <location name="large hall"/>
      <location name="INt/EXT Scenes of Annie and Charles speaking to large crowds."/>
      <location name="national reformer office"/>
      <location name="women rushing to buy the book. Mixed cuts of  newspaper headlines &quot;IMMORAL&quot; Publishers FACE Prison ETC."/>
      <location name="INT. CourTroom."/>
      <location name="Court Room. We see a judge passing sentance on three young men in the dock"/>
      <location name="The court steps"/>
      <location name="EX and Int. Working class streets and interiors"/>
      <location name="The original church"/>
      <location name="Miss Marryot's home school"/>
      <location name="English road, with sea on one side and rolling hills."/>
      <location name="English RAILWAY station."/>
      <location name="Various scenes AROUND SCHOOL"/>
      <location name="Fernhill HoUse kitchen"/>
      <location name="German citIES and SIGHT"/>
      <location name="Cafe in paris."/>
      <location name="Notra Dame."/>
      <location name="Wood home"/>
      <location name="Dusty church."/>
      <location name="Different scenes at the seaside."/>
      <location name="EXT train station"/>
      <location name="INT; THE wood's home"/>
      <location name="A bedroom"/>
      <location name="Cuts of SOFT FOCUS CHURCH WEDDING, ANNIE AS VICARS WIFE THROWING GIFTS TO THE POOR. ALL INTERCUT with brutal intercourse."/>
      <location name="The party return by boat to England."/>
      <location name="by boat to England."/>
      <location name="Interior. We see the Bishop genially greet her as she enters HIS OFFICE. We view them both through the glAss in the door. We cannot heAR the Conversation disTinctly but as the discussion evoLves the bishop can be seen getting more and more angry. THE DOOR IS EVENTUALLY THROWN OPEN."/>
      <location name="and Int. Working class streets and interiors"/>
      <location name="Annie visits A parishioners. Sits by the bedside as a woman loses her baby, attends funeral with baby casket."/>
      <location name="Sisely vicarage"/>
      <location name="Annie home in london"/>
      <location name="Newspaper office"/>
      <location name="INT DINING ROOM"/>
      <location name="Shaw:"/>
      <location name="Ext; press reporters talk to Bradlaugh"/>
      <location name="/INT    Crowds listening to Annie"/>
      <location name="INT Shaw's Bedroom"/>
      <location name="Whithall and trafagar Square. LONDON"/>
      <location name="police station"/>
      <location name="INT Bryant &amp; mat boardroom"/>
      <location name="INT link office"/>
      <location name="INT School boardmeeting"/>
      <location name="INt Magazine OFFICE"/>
      <location name="INT: annie's hall way"/>
      <location name="Blavastki drawing room"/>
      <location name="Blavatsky's drawing room"/>
      <location name="bond street"/>
      <location name="national secular society offices"/>
      <location name="vicarage dining table."/>
      <location name="Dressing room"/>
      <location name="Dressing room. Oscar"/>
      <location name="Two miners walking home after work"/>
      <location name="Various scenes."/>
      <location name="INT lecture hall"/>
      <location name="University Professors room"/>
      <location name="Dockside."/>
      <location name="EXT Boat drawing in to harbour"/>
      <location name="Horse drawn cab"/>
      <location name="Hotel"/>
      <location name="Sri Lankan countryside, visting schools."/>
      <location name="Balcony at hill station bungalow"/>
      <location name="Street scenes in INDIA"/>
      <location name="INT hall in ENGLAND"/>
      <location name="ANNIE' OFFICE in LONON"/>
      <location name="ANNIE' OFFICE in LONDON"/>
      <location name="TS headquarters INdia"/>
      <location name="INT TS headquarters"/>
      <location name="Grounds of TS"/>
      <location name="Int TS house"/>
      <location name="sophisicated Party in UK house"/>
      <location name="hall"/>
      <location name="TS OFFICE London"/>
      <location name="Foreign secretaries office"/>
      <location name="British colonial Office"/>
      <location name="EXT: Major city"/>
      <location name="Annies Interment cottage"/>
      <location name="Streets in Madras full of crowds. ANNIE is greeted like a film star."/>
      <location name="huge hall"/>
      <location name="EXT clafornian garden at TS Centre"/>
      <location name="INT William Roberts' OFFICES and streets"/>
      <location name="OPENING TITLES OF MOVIE"/>
      <location name="EXT: garden at TS Centre IN CALIFORNIA"/>
      <location name="EXT SiBsey Church"/>
      <location name="We also see Annie and Amy at a  large chateau  mixing with the boys. The girls move on to Paris, visit the Louvre. The scene is another demonstrating of the gulf between the life led by Annie and the poor she will soon embrace."/>
      <location name="The girls move on to Paris, visit the Louvre. The scene is another demonstrating of the gulf between the life led by Annie and the poor she will soon embrace."/>
      <location name="EXTERIOR SCENES IN Paris. visit the Louvre. The scene is another demonstrating of the gulf between the life led by Annie and the poor she will soon embrace."/>
      <location name="London tea house."/>
      <location name="Ext: Kalang Airport 1929"/>
      <location name="Theosophical Society Singapore"/>
      <location name="EXT prison yard"/>
      <location name="InSide the police wagon."/>
      <location name="EXT: Same location an hour later"/>
      <location name="INTERIOR GUARDS VAN."/>
      <location name="Ext: Public scaffold"/>
      <location name="INT: annIES Bedroom."/>
      <location name="INT: Miss Marryats dining room"/>
      <location name="Annie's bedroom"/>
      <location name="INT: Louvre"/>
      <location name="INTerior: National ENQUIROR."/>
      <location name="Miners house. We become aware of the contrast between THE two classes as we see the damp dingy interior of the miners  house."/>
      <location name="Ms Marryat's Garden."/>
      <location name="INT School Room"/>
      <location name="INT: Garden"/>
      <location name="schoolroom:"/>
      <location name="Woods"/>
      <location name="INT, SChoolroom"/>
      <location name="School room. TheRE are many books and paintings around the walls."/>
      <location name="INt/EXT Scenes of Annie and Charles speaking to large crowds. Including One for home rule for Ireland."/>
      <location name="Ext:Riverbank"/>
      <location name="INT/EXT. Bradlaughs home&quot;"/>
      <location name="Ext: Brookwood CEmentary"/>
      <location name="EXT, TRAin STATION"/>
      <location name="EXT: STREET IN SINGAPORE"/>
    </locations>
    <scene_intros>
      <scene_intro name="INT."/>
      <scene_intro name="EXT."/>
      <scene_intro name="INT./EXT."/>
    </scene_intros>
    <scene_times>
      <scene_time name="DAY"/>
      <scene_time name="NIGHT"/>
      <scene_time name="MORNING"/>
      <scene_time name="AFTERNOON"/>
      <scene_time name="EVENING"/>
      <scene_time name="LATER"/>
      <scene_time name="MOMENTS LATER"/>
      <scene_time name="CONTINUOUS"/>
      <scene_time name="THE NEXT DAY"/>
    </scene_times>
    <extensions>
      <extension name="(V.O.)"/>
      <extension name="(O.S.)"/>
      <extension name="(O.C.)"/>
      <extension name="(SUBTITLE)"/>
    </extensions>
    <transitions>
      <transition name="CUT TO:"/>
      <transition name="FADE IN:"/>
      <transition name="FADE OUT"/>
      <transition name="FADE TO:"/>
      <transition name="DISSOLVE TO:"/>
      <transition name="BACK TO:"/>
      <transition name="MATCH CUT TO:"/>
      <transition name="JUMP CUT TO:"/>
      <transition name="FADE TO BLACK"/>
    </transitions>
    <revision_colors>
      <revision_color name="White" index="0" color_name="White" color_index="0" mark=""/>
      <revision_color name="Blue" index="1" color_name="Blue" color_index="1" mark="*"/>
      <revision_color name="Pink" index="2" color_name="Pink" color_index="2" mark="*"/>
      <revision_color name="Yellow" index="3" color_name="Yellow" color_index="3" mark="*"/>
      <revision_color name="Green" index="4" color_name="Green" color_index="4" mark="*"/>
      <revision_color name="Goldenrod" index="5" color_name="Goldenrod" color_index="5" mark="*"/>
      <revision_color name="Buff" index="6" color_name="Buff" color_index="6" mark="*"/>
      <revision_color name="Salmon" index="7" color_name="Salmon" color_index="7" mark="*"/>
      <revision_color name="Cherry" index="8" color_name="Cherry" color_index="8" mark="*"/>
      <revision_color name="Tan" index="9" color_name="Tan" color_index="9" mark="*"/>
    </revision_colors>
    <tag_categories>
      <tag_category name="Cast"/>
      <tag_category name="Background Actors"/>
      <tag_category name="Stunts"/>
      <tag_category name="Vehicles"/>
      <tag_category name="Props"/>
      <tag_category name="Camera"/>
      <tag_category name="Special Effects"/>
      <tag_category name="Wardrobe"/>
      <tag_category name="Makeup/Hair"/>
      <tag_category name="Animals"/>
      <tag_category name="Animal Handler"/>
      <tag_category name="Music"/>
      <tag_category name="Sound"/>
      <tag_category name="Set Dressing"/>
      <tag_category name="Greenery"/>
      <tag_category name="Special Equipment"/>
      <tag_category name="Security"/>
      <tag_category name="Additional Labor"/>
      <tag_category name="Visual Effects"/>
      <tag_category name="Mechanical Effects"/>
      <tag_category name="Miscellaneous"/>
      <tag_category name="Notes"/>
    </tag_categories>
    <highlight_rules/>
  </lists>
</document>
